Good morning, everyone, and welcome to the NDN Community Meeting,
大家早上好，欢迎参加NDN社区会议，
hosted by NIST as a two-day virtual event with an exciting
由NIST主办的为期两天的线上虚拟活动，内容精彩纷呈，
agenda made up of seven technical sessions, two or
由七个技术会议、两个或
three panels, and the posters and demonstration.
三个小组讨论会，以及海报和演示。
The agenda details and abstracts of all presentations are available under
议程的详细信息和所有演讲的摘要可以在下方找到
the Agenda tab on the Events page, as shown here, in this slide.
事件页面上的议程标签，如此幻灯片所示。
And the NDN Community Meeting is organized
与NIST和NDN联盟合作举办的NDN社区会议
in collaboration with NIST and the NDN Consortium.
与NIST和NDN联盟合作。
And as some of you may know, this year, we completed the transfer
而且正如你们中的一些人可能知道的，今年，我们完成了将NDN联盟管理工作从加州大学洛杉矶分校转移到NIST的工作。
of the NDN consortium management from UCLA to NIST.
And as some of you may know, this year, we completed the transition of the NDN consortium management from the University of California, Los Angeles to NIST.
It happened earlier this year, and the consortium will play the role of single
今年早些时候发生的，该联盟将扮演单一的
point of collaborative participation for industry, universities,
参与协作的中心点，包括工业界、大学、
government agencies and others interested in NDN to be connected and
参与协作的中心点，包括工业界、大学、政府机构以及其他对NDN感兴趣的人，以便相互联系并参与NDN的研究与开发。
to participate in NDN research and development.
参与NDN的研究与开发。
It will also provide general support of the NDN effort especially for
它还将为NDN项目提供特别的一般支持，尤其是在
outreach communication and open source development.
它还将为NDN项目提供特别的一般支持，尤其是在与NDN社区合作解决和规范NDN的外联沟通和开源开发方面。
This will work with the NDN community to address and standardize NDN and
外部联络沟通及开源开发的问题，并与NDN社区合作进行解决和规范。
have the industry evaluate the technology.
进行行业评估该技术。
And as some of you know, we have a number of efforts,
正如你们中的一些人所知，我们进行了许多努力，
one of them being the NDN-DPDK forwarder that some of you are using,
其中一个是你们中的一些人正在使用的NDN-DPDK转发器，
and we have some ongoing work on NDN measurement and management.
我们还在进行一些关于NDN测量和管理的工作。
A template CRADA, Cooperative Research and Development Agreement, is ready.
一份合作研究与开发协议（CRADA）的模板已经准备好了。
It has been developed and signed by NIST and UCLA.
它已由NIST和UCLA共同开发并签署。
And I'd like to take this opportunity to thank the UCLA
并且我想借此机会感谢加州大学洛杉矶分校
team who took care of the consortium management when it was hosted at UCLA,
团队在它托管在加州大学洛杉矶分校时负责联盟管理工作，
in particular Lixia Zhang and Jeff Burke.
特别是李夏·张和杰夫·伯克。
And I think Jeff is on the line and
我认为杰夫正在通话中，
then the probably wants to say a word here, Jeff?
他可能想在这里说几句话，对吗，杰夫？
>> Sure, yeah, thanks.
当然，是的，谢谢。
So the consortium, the mission is essentially the same
所以该联盟，其使命基本上是一致的。
as the consortium that was started by the academic institutions, but
作为由学术机构发起的联盟，但是
with the hope that by hosting it at NIST, it will have sorta increased
希望通过在NIST举办，它将会有某种程度的增长。
administrative stability and reached the work with government and
行政稳定并且与政府合作达成了工作
industry partners, as well as number of nonprofits and universities.
行业合作伙伴，以及许多非营利组织和大学。
So we're excited to complete the transfer and ready to
所以我们很高兴完成转移并准备
start publishing new information about the consortium and get organizations aboard.
开始发布有关财团的新信息，并让组织加入。
Based on feedback, we've created a new fee structure for the voting members that
基于反馈，我们为投票成员创建了一个新的费用结构，以便能够对财团的方向进行关键决策投票。
wish to be able to voting key decisions regarding the direction of the consortium
希望能够对财团的方向进行关键决策投票。
that's listed here on the slides including a reduction of the fee remission in this
这里在幻灯片上列出的内容包括在此减少费用减免。
pilot fiscal year in light of the challenging global circumstances.
在充满挑战的全球环境下，试点财政年度。
Also, there's an opportunity for especially oriented towards nonprofits and
此外，这也是一个特别面向非营利组织的机会，以及
universities to provide in-kind contributions of equivalent value that
允许大学提供等值的实物捐助，以便
allow voting participation through in-kind contributions.
允许通过实物捐献参与投票。
It's also a mechanism for industry partners to provide services or
它也是一种机制，用于行业合作伙伴提供服务或者
support to the consortium for some reduction of the cash fee.
支持财团以减少现金费用的方式。
So hopefully this provides more flexibility for
所以希望这能提供更多的灵活性，以便
a large number of organizations to participate.
参与其中的大量组织。
If we can go to the next slide.
如果我们可以进入下一张幻灯片。
So hopefully in time for a ACM ICN, you should see the release of
所以希望在ACM ICN举行之前，你们将能看到发布……
a new identity for the consortium, as well as a civilian
一个新的财团身份，以及一个平民
friendly website that makes the case for the the technology,
友好的网站宣传这项技术的优势，
the consortium, the ongoing research that's continuing around the world.
该联盟正在全球范围内持续进行的研究。
And so, this is a little bit of a teaser of the identity and we should have that
这就是身份的一点预告，我们应该会在月底前让人们开始关注。
up for people to start taking a look at towards the end of the month.
我们预计月底前人们将开始关注这个问题。
So we're excited about that, as well.
所以我们对此也感到兴奋。
That's it for me, thank you.
我就说这么多，谢谢。
>> Thank you, Jeff.
>> 谢谢你，Jeff。
Back to the agenda.
回到议程上来。
For the posters and demo session this afternoon, we have seven
对于今天下午的海报和演示环节，我们有七个
with two groups in the same BlueJeans Room because they have the same presenter.
因为他们有同一个演讲者，所以有两个小组在同一个BlueJeans房间里。
So we have a total of six BlueJeans links as shown in this table.
所以我们总共有六个BlueJeans链接，如下表所示。
They will each have a short presentation at the lightning talk session.
他们每个人都会在快速演讲环节进行一个简短的报告。
But four of them have provided the longer pre-recorded version of the thoughts
但是其中四人提供了他们想法的较长的预录制版本。
that we made available online at this link here.
我们在这个链接上提供了在线访问。
And if you go to that link,
如果您访问那个链接，
you will see the four videos in the browser window as shown on the left.
您将会在浏览器窗口中看到左边显示的四个视频。
And when you click on one of them, the video will be streamed
当您点击其中一个视频时，视频将开始在线播放。
over at the end without installing any software on your laptop.
在结束时，您无需在笔记本电脑上安装任何软件。
It uses the video streaming platform iViSa, iCN Video Streaming Application,
它使用视频流媒体平台iViSa，即iCN视频流应用程序，
developed at University of Arizona, which runs over the global and the untested.
它是在亚利桑那大学开发的，运行在全球范围内且尚未经过测试。
And we should probably try to run NDN next time over NDN, as well.
我们下次也应该尝试通过NDN运行NDN。
For panels, we have two today moderated by NDN co-chairs Christos and Kathy.
对于小组讨论，我们今天有两个，由NDN联席主席Christos和Kathy主持。
And tomorrow we have one moderated by Christian on lessons learned over
明天我们还有一个由Christian主持的讨论，主题是过去十年学到的经验教训。
the last ten years.
我们过去十年。
As many of you know, this year 2020 is the ten-year anniversary of
正如你们许多人所知，今年2020年是我们过去十年。
the NSF Funded Agent Project, which started years ago in 2010.
美国国家科学基金会资助的代理项目，始于2010年。
Before I hand it to Susmit for session one,
在我把它交给Susmit进行第一场会议之前，
I'd like to thank the co-chairs, Christos and Kathy,
我想感谢联合主席Christos和Kathy，
the panel chairs, and the panelists, the session chairs, and all the presenters.
会议主席、小组讨论主席、小组成员、分会场主席以及所有报告者。
And thanks also to Debbie and for their help with the local arrangement.
同时也感谢Debbie以及他们在当地安排上的帮助。
Finally, just one reminder about Q&A.
最后，关于问答环节，提醒一点。
You could use either the chat window shown in this picture,
您可以使用图片中显示的聊天窗口，
or the raise hand feature.
或使用举手功能。
And the chair will pick from both the chat and the raise hand list.
主持人将同时从聊天和举手名单中选择提问者。
With that, I think it's time to hand it to Susmit for
接下来，我认为是时候交给Susmit主持会议了。
session one on NDN Trial Deployments.
第一场关于NDN试点部署的会议。
Susmit?
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Thank you, Lofti.
>> 谢谢你，洛夫蒂。
Good morning, everyone.
大家早上好。
My name is Susmit Shannigrahi, I'm an assistant professor at Tennessee Tech.
我的名字是Susmit Shannigrahi，我是田纳西科技大学的助理教授。
So in this session, we're going to have four talks.
所以在这个环节，我们将有四场演讲。
We are thinking about 10 to 12 minutes for the talks and then 2 minutes for
我们考虑每场演讲大约10到12分钟，然后是2分钟用于
discussions.
讨论环节。
I'll be giving a reminder before two minutes.
我会在两分钟前提醒您。
So let me introduce this first speaker, Dr. Alex Feltus from Clemson University.
那么让我先介绍第一位演讲者，来自克莱姆森大学的Alex Feltus博士。
He received a BAC in biochemistry from Auburn University,
他从奥本大学获得了生物化学学士学位，
served in Peace Corps in Fiji Islands.
在斐济群岛服役于和平队。
And then completed advanced training in Biomedical Sciences at
然后在生物医学科学方面完成了高级培训
Vanderbilt and Emory.
范德比尔特大学和埃默里大学。
He has performed research in artificial intelligence, bioinformatics,
他进行了人工智能、生物信息学的研究，
cyberinfrastructure, high performance computing, network biology, tumor biology,
网络基础设施、高性能计算、网络生物学、肿瘤生物学，
agrigenomics, system genomics, and bioenergy feedstock genetics.
农业基因组学、系统基因组学和生物能源原料遗传学。
Currently, he's a professor in Clemson University's Department of genetics and
目前，他是克莱姆森大学遗传学系的教授，
biochemistry and co-founder of practice AI, LLC.
目前，他是克莱姆森大学遗传学系的教授，生物化学专家以及实践AI有限责任公司的联合创始人。He will be sharing his experience in publishing genomics data sets into an NDN.
He will be sharing his experience in publishing genomics data sets into an NDN
他将分享他将基因组数据集发布到NDN中的经验。
testbed and integrating with cloud workflows.
测试床并与云工作流程集成。
Alex, please.
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Hey, can you see my slides?
>> 嘿，你能看到我的幻灯片吗？
Is it good?
它好吗？
>> Yes.
是的。
>> Hey everybody, so yeah, thanks for having me here.
大家好，是的，感谢邀请我来到这里。
This is an honor actually to be the first speaker,
这实际上是一个荣幸，成为第一位发言者，
that's never happened to me before.
这是我以前从未遇到过的。
That's pretty cool.
这非常酷。
But so I'm an end user, I'm a biologist.
但是我是一个终端用户，我是一位生物学家。
I'm trying to understand lots of different biological things.
我正在尝试理解许多不同的生物学事物。
I have an interest in cancer biology and agricultural genomics too, a lot for
我也对癌症生物学和农业基因组学感兴趣，这是一个很大的领域。
food security and health, human health.
粮食安全与健康，人类健康。
They're both really important for human health.
它们对于人类健康都非常重要。
And to do my work, I have to use, I'm working at the terascale, petascale, now,
为了完成我的工作，我必须使用，我现在正在使用的是兆级（terascale）、拍级（petascale）计算规模，
and I'll be working at the exascale I think before I retire,
为了完成我的工作，我必须使用，我现在正在使用的是兆级（terascale）、拍级（petascale）计算规模，而我认为在我退休之前，我将会使用到艾级（exascale）计算规模，given the exponential growth of data sets.
given the exponential growth of data sets.
鉴于数据集的指数级增长。
So NDN to me is a really important
所以对我来说，NDN真的很重要
layer of storage where you can have data accessed by name and
层存储，你可以通过名称访问数据，以及
not all the vagaries of repositories that you have to
不必理会你必须面对的所有仓库的变幻莫测，
understand how to navigate to be able to get the data in the first place.
理解如何导航才能首先获取数据。
So anyway, this is an incredible opportunity to be part of this
所以无论如何，这是一个难以置信的机会，能成为这个的一部分。
development.
发展。
I think it's critical for genomics and of course, other fields.
我认为这对基因组学乃至其他领域都至关重要。
My lab is, I just love biology.
我的实验室，我就是热爱生物学。
I'm sort of attracted to chaos, I think, and I just keep,
我有点被混乱所吸引，我想，我就一直这样，
see how far I can expand things.
看看我能将事物扩展到多大程度。
But I study plants, animals, vertebrates, and angiosperms.
但我研究植物、动物、脊椎动物和被子植物。
And these are some of the organisms that I've studied over the years,
这些是我这些年来研究过的一些生物。
if I can get a pointer up here.
如果我能在这里得到一个指示。
And again, to do all this work, we have to do a lot of algorithm development.
为了完成所有这些工作，我们必须进行大量的算法开发。
We do a lot of workflow engineering.
我们进行了大量的工作流程工程设计。
We're doing a lot of stuff in the cloud.
我们在云端进行了大量的工作。
We have to understand CUDA and we have to understand bioformatics and
我们必须理解CUDA，也必须理解生物信息学和
all sorts of stuff to be able to get our work done.
我们必须理解CUDA，也必须理解生物信息学和各种各样的东西才能完成我们的工作。
Because the problem is that biological measurements now,
因为现在的问题是生物测量，
DNA sequencers are pushing us towards the exascale.
DNA测序仪正在将我们推向艾字节级（exabyte-scale）。
We're in the terascale, most biologists are now for measurement.
我们目前处于太字节级别，大多数生物学家现在用于测量。
And most people don't know how to deal with terascale when there's a terabyte of
大多数人在处理太字节级别的数据时并不知道该如何应对。
hard drive space on their laptops.
大多数人在他们的笔记本电脑上都有硬盘空间。
So in my research we're using a lot of AI right now, actually a lot of image
所以在我的研究中，我们现在实际上正在使用大量的人工智能，确实是很多图像
analysis techniques to be able to deal with gene expression data.
分析技术来处理基因表达数据。
And there's a recent paper we published where we're actually taking data
并且我们最近发表了一篇论文，在那篇论文中，我们实际上正在收集数据
from patients and integrating it with other data sets like tumor data,
来自患者的数据，并将其与肿瘤数据等其他数据集进行整合，
and in this case, kidney cancer data specifically.
并且在这种情况下，特别是肾癌数据。
And actually tomorrow at Clemson, there's a speaker, the patient,
明天在克莱姆森大学，有一个演讲者，病人，
is gonna be presenting at our department seminar about our work.
他将在我们系的研讨会上介绍我们的工作。
Together, he's a collaborator that we're trying to draw targets for him.
他是我们的合作者，我们正试图为他勾画目标。
So we do a lot of that kinda work, a lot of personalized precision medicine work,
所以我们做了很多那种类型的工作，很多个性化精准医疗的工作，
and with protected data sets and unprotected data sets.
和使用受保护的数据集以及非受保护的数据集。
And we also do a lot of work trying to understand root biology and how roots will
我们还做了大量的工作来试图理解根部生物学以及根部如何
fix nitrogen from the air with a symbiotic relationship with bacteria.
固定空气中的氮气，并与细菌形成共生关系。
This is an NSF-funded project.
这是一个由美国国家科学基金会资助的项目。
And I'm also very interested in training people how to use clouds or
我也非常感兴趣于培训人们如何使用云服务或者
HPC in cloud systems to get their work done.
HPC（高性能计算）在云系统中完成他们的工作。
And I have a company called Practice AI, where we actually have scalable data
我有一家名为Practice AI的公司，我们实际上拥有可扩展的数据
intensive computing training and we're open for business.
我们提供密集计算培训，并且已对外开放业务。
This is a big part of biology now.
这现在是生物学的一个重要部分。
This is database records from the NCBI, National Center for
这是来自美国国家生物技术信息中心（NCBI），国家中心的数据库记录。
Biotechnology Information.
生物技术信息。
Sequence read archive database is one database.
序列读取档案数据库是一个数据库。
They used to be mirrored in Japan and UK, and
他们曾经在日本和英国有镜像站点，而且……
it's no longer mirror-able, if that's a word.
它已经不能被镜像了，如果那算是一个词的话。
Because this is, just one of the databases has 44.2 petabytes of
因为这只是其中一个数据库就有44.2拍字节的数据。
DNA sequence data and you know this will be exabytes.
DNA序列数据，你知道这将是以艾字节为单位的数据量。
There's an exponential curve in the not too distant future.
在不远的将来，将有一个指数型曲线。
So we want to mine this data, we do mine this data.
所以我们想要挖掘这些数据，我们确实在挖掘这些数据。
There's almost 7 million experiments now, for mining.
现在已经有将近700万个实验可以用来挖掘了。
It's available to anybody in the world, right?
它对世界上任何人都是可用的，对吧？
And so we're trying to deal with this massive volume, and the cure for
我们正在尝试处理这庞大的数据量，以及对于
cancer is sitting there at 6.9 million experiments.
癌症的实验数量已经达到了690万。
It's just connecting the right dots.
它只是在连接正确的点。
There's 478,000 species now with at least one sequence in these databases,
现在这些数据库中至少有478,000个物种拥有至少一个序列，
they're just exploding with amazing, valuable information.
它们中充满了惊人的、极有价值的信息。
This is one database.
这是一个数据库。
We're also pulling data from NASA's gene lab database,
我们还从NASA的基因实验室数据库中提取数据，
which has similar types of data, but at a different repository.
它拥有类似类型的数据，但存放在不同的仓库中。
The Ensembl database in UK we pull from, we also have community databases, laser,
我们从英国的Ensembl数据库中提取数据，我们还有社区数据库，laser，
agricultural, genomic.
农业基因组学。
So the idea is to cut to the chase, that's the right first thing,
所以这个想法是直奔主题，这是正确的第一步，
is that we're putting data in a testbed.
我们正在尝试将数据放入测试平台中。
We're actually trying to put all of this data in a testbed.
我们实际上正在尝试将所有这些数据放入测试平台中。
Not at one time, but actually have pointers to the data to be able
不是一次性地，而是实际上拥有指向待处理数据的指针，以便
to pull it in as users request it using NDN naming strategies,
来按需使用NDN命名策略拉取它。
which I'll show you in a second.
我马上会向你展示。
But this is kind of the overview of our compute environment.
但这大致是我们计算环境的概览。
We're pulling data from lots of different repositories, local storage,
我们正在从许多不同的仓库、本地存储中提取数据，
putting into the NDN testbed and publishing it there.
正在将其放入NDN测试床并在那里发布。
And pulling it into cloud systems where we work on campus HPC,
正在将其集成到云系统中，在那里我们在校园HPC上工作，
traditional HPC, but also did a lot of work in Google Cloud.
传统的高性能计算(HPC)，我们也在谷歌云上做了大量工作。
And also some commercialized clouds like the Pacific Research Platform and
以及一些商业化云服务，比如太平洋研究平台和
TACC have Kubernetes systems.
TACC拥有Kubernetes系统。
And we're pulling this data using some tools we've developed as part of our
我们正在使用我们作为项目一部分开发的一些工具提取这些数据。
NSF science project into PVCs in the cloud and
我们正在将NSF科学项目中的PVCs迁移到云端。
running workflows contain everything we're doing here is containerized.
正在运行的工作流程包含了我们在这里所做的一切都是容器化的。
This is one example.
这是一个例子。
GEMmaker is sort of a standard procedure that you have to do to build or
GEMmaker 是一种你必须进行的标准程序，用于构建或者
process DNA sequencing information.
处理 DNA 测序信息。
It requires lots and lots of different containerized applications.
它需要许多不同的容器化应用程序。
It's really complicated stuff, but we've got this working pretty well.
这确实是非常复杂的事情，但我们已经让它工作得相当好了。
So we can run this at scale.
所以我们可以大规模地运行这个。
We've run this petabytes of data.
我们已经处理了这数千亿字节的数据。
So in the end, we're publishing data in NDN.
所以最终，我们正在NDN中发布数据。
We also, just yesterday actually, were able to publish from,
所以我们实际上就在昨天，能够从……发布。
with collaboration with Cisco and Internet2 is helping too,
与思科和Internet2的合作也在帮助我们，
publishing in an hICM testbed too we have set up.
我们还建立了一个hICM测试平台，正在上面进行发布。
So we're actually trying to do this in parallel and
所以我们实际上是在尝试并行进行这项工作。
I'd love to have testbeds with the same code running on the same nodes and
我希望能有测试平台，在相同的节点上运行相同的代码，
sort of as a lofty goal that we have.
作为我们拥有的一个远大目标。
About all of our, everything I have on here, all of our data,
关于我们所有的，我在这里拥有的一切，我们所有的数据，
all of our code is open source, and it's all on GitHub.
我们的所有代码都是开源的，而且都托管在GitHub上。
And these are, if I put them on here, they're probably tools that actually work.
如果我把它们放在这里，它们很可能是真正有效的工具。
A big part of we're trying to do is with the NDN is with some of the problems being
我们试图通过NDN解决的一大部分问题是
addressed, one of them is the fair data principles.
我们试图通过NDN解决的一大部分问题是确保数据遵循公平数据原则。So findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability.
So findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability.
因此，可发现性、可访问性、互操作性和可重用性。
And so there's a complicated diagram here, but
因此这里有一个复杂的图表，但
the idea is you have data in different repositories, local storage, right?
这个想法是你有数据存储在不同的地方，比如本地存储，对吗？
And people want to keep their data as biologists for
人们希望像生物学家一样保留他们的数据，以便在发布之前存档一段时间。
a while before they publish.
在他们发布之前存档一段时间。
And so things like findability, you can't find stuff on people's hard drives, right?
因此，像可查找性这样的问题，你无法在人们的硬盘驱动器上找到东西，对吧？
Finding it in public databases is very doable.
在公共数据库中找到它是非常可行的。
Accessing it can be tricky, and I've been working with NCBI databases for
在公共数据库中找到它是非常可行的。25年了，我仍然不太懂他们的架构。
25 years and I still don't quite understand their schema.
25年了，我仍然不太懂他们的架构。
So learning the tricks to be able to pull data is important.
因此学习能够提取数据的技巧是很重要的。
Interoperability, a lot of genomics data is in common file formats and and
互操作性，许多基因组数据都采用了常见的文件格式，并且
sometimes you have to preprocess it.
有时你需要对数据进行预处理。
We're putting a lot of preprocessed data into NDN, the NDN testbed.
我们正在将大量预处理过的数据输入到NDN，即NDN测试平台中。
And reusability is a lot of this data storage so
并且这种数据存储的可重用性非常高，所以
you can go and reuse it, repurpose it for other purposes.
你可以去重复使用它，将它用于其他目的。
And so we're trying to address all these problems with NDN, right?
我们正在尝试用NDN来解决所有这些问题，对吗？
Especially the accessibility part is abstracting all the metadata weirdness and
特别是可访问性部分，它抽象了所有的元数据怪异性并且……
putting it into here so you can extract it with names.
将其放入这里，这样您就可以提取出带有名称的信息。
One thing cool about biology data is it's organized, well, biology is crazy, right?
生物数据的一个酷炫之处在于它是有组织的，嗯，生物学本身就很疯狂，对吧？
It's like the craziest thing ever, like we were trying to explain biology.
这就像是有史以来最疯狂的事情，就像我们在尝试解释生物学一样。
But if you organize data by evolutionary principles, it becomes actually rational.
但如果你按照进化原则来组织数据，它实际上就变得合乎逻辑了。
And so we actually have hierarchies of data sets from different species.
因此，我们实际上拥有来自不同物种的数据集的层级结构。
Like armadillos and humans are both animals, there's a common ancestor
像犰狳和人类都是动物，它们有一个共同的祖先。
thought to be from animals and humans 60 million years ago.
被认为是来自6000万年前的动物和人类。
Find a time machine, I would go back and see if I could spot this little guy
找到一台时光机，我会回到过去看看能否找到这个小家伙。
running around, probably sequence with genome too just for fun.
到处乱跑，可能也会为了好玩而试着和基因组序列进行匹配。
But we have relationships between the data sets, so
但是我们的数据集之间存在着关联性，所以
we can organize things by genus and species.
我们可以按属和种来组织事物。
Geno phylum in family order, I can't even do it right now,
门纲目科属，我现在甚至都做不到。
all the different levels of taxonomy levels.
所有不同等级的分类等级。
Which we have baked into our naming conventions,
我们已将其融入到我们的命名规则中，
as a natural way to name data.
作为一种自然的数据命名方式。
For example, there's over 4700 genomes we're indexing right now,
例如，我们目前正在索引的基因组数量超过了4700个，
pre-processing for workflows.
预处理工作流程。
And we have a naming convention for them.
我们为它们设定了命名规则。
I won't go into all the details, but we're actually processing all of these and
我不会详述所有细节，但我们实际上正在处理所有这些内容，并且
publishing them right now into one place of access, named access.
我们正在将它们发布到一个名为“access”的访问点上。
All of the RNA expression databases, data sets out there if anybody knows
所有的RNA表达数据库、数据集，如果有人知道的话。
what RNA-seq is, we have a naming convention too based upon biodomain.
RNA-seq是什么，我们也有基于生物领域的命名约定。
And then the different levels of naming, and we actually have a UI setup for
然后是不同层级的命名，实际上我们有一个用户界面设置用于
this to be able to search the names, and be able to get.
这样就能够搜索这些名称，并且能够得到。
Really, what we're trying to do is deal with these endpoint unique identifiers,
实际上，我们尝试要做的是处理这些端点唯一标识符，
which means a lot to the biologists to be able to pull data.
这对生物学家来说意义重大，因为他们能够提取数据。
We have a test, an NDN type report.
我们有一个测试，一个NDN类型的报告。
There were, I don't think we actually published yet.
我们好像还没有正式发布。
We're still it finishing it up about how we're actually publishing data
我们还在整理关于我们如何实际发布数据的细节。
into the databases.
进入数据库中。
This is one of the test nodes that we're using right now to be able
我们现在正在使用的测试节点之一，以便能够进入数据库中。发布我们的数据。
to publish our data.
发布我们的数据。
And so we're able to have students now,
因此，我们现在能够让学生参与进来，
biology students who publish the data with help from people like Susmit and
因此，我们现在能够让学生参与进来，像Susmit这样的生物学学生在其他真正帮助我们处理技术层面的人们的帮助下发布数据。
others who are really helping us with the technical aspects of it.
其他真正帮助我们处理技术层面的人。
And we're learning how to pull data, so we're focusing on the naming, and
我们正在学习如何提取数据，因此我们专注于命名，以及
pulling, and pushing into workflows.
提取、推送进入工作流程。
And then a lot of the backend stuff, we ask the people in my lab, actually,
然后很多后端的工作，我们实际上是请求我实验室的人来做的，
we have a pretty interdisciplinary lab helping with this.
我们有一个跨学科的实验室帮助做这件事。
But the Indiana community has been fantastic in helping us try to get this
但是印第安纳社区在帮助我们尝试获得这个方面做得非常出色。
working for us, because ultimately, we care about just getting the result,
为我们服务，因为归根结底，我们只关心最终获得结果，
right, and not so much the process underneath that.
对，我们并不是很关心其背后的过程。
These are some test data sets that we have, or experiments.
这些是我们拥有的一些测试数据集或实验。
We actually have two key data sets right now.
我们目前实际上有两个关键数据集。
One is a human kidney data set.
一个是人类肾脏数据集。
It's about, well, 36x2 files,
大约是36乘以2个文件，
1.16 terabytes, but we also have a rice data set.
1.16 TB的数据量，但我们还有一个米的数据集。
It's about 1.14 terabytes, almost 1000 samples.
大约有1.14 TB的数据量，接近1000个样本。
A lot of genomes are there.
有许多基因组存在。
We're trying to plug in all the genomes into the testbed, as well as trying to get
我们正在尝试将所有的基因组数据接入测试平台，同时也在努力获取更多的数据。
lofty with a lot of our goals, and trying to get more data in there.
我们的目标很宏伟，正在努力获取更多的数据。
This is real quick preliminary results here.
这里是非常初步的快速结果。
So this is downloading the rice data sets here.
这里正在下载水稻数据集。
This is time in minutes.
这是以分钟为单位的时间。
It's very fast to get them onto the computer that we're then we're gonna
将它们快速地传输到我们随后将要使用的计算机上。
publish them on with the publishing and pulling rates here.
将它们以此处的发布和拉取速率发布出去。
This is for almost 1000 data sets.
这是将近1000个数据集。
It's taken a long time, right, to be able to do this.
这花了很长时间，对吧，才能做到这一点。
And we're optimizing right now.
我们现在正在进行优化。
And we've performed some experiments with caching,
我们已经进行了一些关于缓存的实验，
where we actually did with using commercial Internet.
我们实际上是使用商业互联网完成的。
This is using no caching, and this is first transferred, and
这是不使用缓存的情况，而这是首次传输，
the cache kicks in, and we get much, much faster pull rates from NDN.
缓存生效后，我们从NDN获取数据的速度会快很多。
And then so opportunities, we can talk about this after this.
之后我们有机会，可以在这之后再谈论这个。
But we can exchange ideas to work containerizing stuff, and
但我们可以交流想法，共同努力将事物容器化，以及
learning how to do stuff like put data on PVCs.
学习如何执行诸如将数据放置在持久卷存储（PVCs）上的操作。
Other communities need to do this.
其他社区也需要做这件事。
I think Edmund's gonna be talking about this.
我认为埃德蒙很可能会谈论这个话题。
We need better tools for publishing data, and more optimized tools to make it.
我们需要更好的工具来发布数据，以及更优化的工具来制作它。
Optimization is pretty key for us right now.
我们现在非常需要优化。
We need bigger places to host data.
我们需要更大的空间来存储数据。
We wanna host exabytes of data eventually, right?
我们最终想要托管的数据量达到艾字节级别，对吗？
I wanna be able to post about 10 petabytes a day, it would be ideal.
我希望每天能够发布大约10拍字节的数据，这将是理想的状态。
Be bigger data lakes writing grants to do this kinda stuff right now.
目前正在编写资金申请，以支持建设更大的数据湖这类项目。
And we need testbeds to be able to test out these containerized solutions,
我们需要测试平台来测试这些容器化解决方案。
because if you do this in the cloud, you'll be broke.
因为如果你在云端这么做，你会破产的。
You'll be going to debtors prison real fast.
你会很快进入债务人监狱的。
And so we're using democratized systems like the Pacific Research Platform.
因此，我们正在使用像太平洋研究平台这样的民主化系统。
And TACC has a Kubernetes cluster that we're running a lot of our tests on.
因此，TACC拥有一个Kubernetes集群，我们在上面运行了很多测试。
And with that, my team is highly interdisciplinary.
因此，我的团队具有高度的跨学科性。
Funded by NSF, Cisco has been very generous with money, DOE USDA,
由国家科学基金会资助，思科在资金方面非常慷慨，能源部、农业部也是如此，
working with lots of institutions, lots of people to get this done,
合作着许多机构、许多人一起完成这项工作，
trying to help genomics out to cure cancer and feed the world.
努力帮助基因组学研究以治愈癌症和养活世界。
I'll stop there.
我就说到这里。
>> Thank you, Alex.
>> 谢谢你，亚历克斯。
So are there any questions?
那么有什么问题吗？
I have a question for you, Alex.
我有个问题要问你，亚历克斯。
So you mentioned the support from Indian community.
所以你提到了来自印度社区的支持。
So can you elaborate on that?
那么你能详细说明一下吗？
What kind of support would you like to see?
你希望得到什么样的支持？
Is it optimization?
它是优化吗？
Is it better APIs?
它是更好的API吗？
>> I think for me, if you ask my students, they might say something different.
我认为对我来说，如果你问我的学生，他们可能会有不同的看法。
But it's optimization at this point, cuz we have it functional.
但这个阶段主要是进行优化，因为我们已经让它运作起来了。
We can pull data into workflows.
我们可以将数据拉入工作流中。
And we're focusing on that integration, modifying the workflows to pull data in
我们正在专注于该集成，修改工作流以拉取数据。
from the network, as opposed to the file system on the PVC, like is shown here.
从网络上获取数据，而不是像这里显示的那样从PVC上的文件系统中获取。
And so we need to be able to do that publish and
我们需要能够完成那个发布和
pull faster, but I think we actually have the pieces now.
我们现在实际上已经有了完成的部件，但我认为我们确实需要更快地进行。
I think we just need to make it faster, yeah.
我认为我们只需要让它更快一些，是的。
>> Okay, thank you.
>> 好的，谢谢。
So there is no other questions, then I think we can thank the speaker.
所以如果没有其他问题的话，我想我们可以感谢演讲者了。
Thank you, Alex.
谢谢你，亚历克斯。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> So the next talk is by Edmund Yeh.
>> 接下来的演讲将由Edmund Yeh进行。
Edmund is currently a professor of Electrical and
Edmund 目前是电气与计算机工程学教授，在东北大学。
He was previously assistant and associate professor
他之前是助理教授和副教授
of Electrical Engineering Computer Science and Statistics at El.
他曾在电子工程、计算机科学和统计学部门任教。
Professor Yeh was one of the PIs on the original NSF funded Project.
叶教授是最初由国家科学基金会资助的项目的主要研究人员之一。
He served as as the general chair for ACM Sigmetrics in 2020,
他在2020年担任了ACM Sigmetrics的大会主席，
and will serve as the TPC co-chair for ACM MobiHoc in 2021.
并将在2021年担任ACM MobiHoc的技术程序委员会联合主席。
His talk today is Data-Centric Ecosystems for Large-Scale Data-Intensive Science.
他今天的演讲主题是“面向大规模数据密集型科学的数据中心生态系统”。
Hello, Edmund?
你好，埃德蒙？
>> Okay, hear me now?
>> 好的，现在能听到我说话了吗？
>> Yes, yeah.
>> 是的，可以。
And we can see the slides as well.
我们也可以看到幻灯片。
>> Okay, great.
>> 好的，太棒了。
So great.
太棒了。
All right, so great pleasure to be here today.
非常荣幸今天能来到这里。
And [COUGH] so I'll be talking about data-centric ecosystems for
接下来我将讨论以数据为中心的生态系统。
large-scale data-intensive science.
大规模的数据密集型科学。
And this is something that we've been working on the last couple of years,
这是我们过去几年一直在努力的事情，
actually.
这实际上是我们过去几年一直在努力的事情，实际上。所以数据密集型科学，我们谈论的是一些世界上最令人兴奋的~!@#$%^&*()
So data-intensive science, we're talking about some of the world's most exciting
~!@#$%^&*(), research projects, including Large Hadron Collider, high energy physics.
research projects, including Large Hadron Collider, high energy physics.
研究项目，包括大型强子对撞机、高能物理学。
The Large Synoptic Survey Telescope in astrophysics, and
天文物理学中的大型综合巡天望远镜，以及
Square Kilometre Array, and also genomics.
平方公里阵列望远镜，以及基因组学。
So there are many such examples of large science projects,
因此有许多这样的大型科学项目的例子，
collaborative projects involving many, many different institutions around
涉及世界各地许多不同机构的合作项目，
the world, That has to handle large volumes of data.
世界上必须处理大量数据的地方。
They face similar set of problems.
他们面临着类似的问题集。
These challenges that go through all of them
他们都面临着这些挑战。
include How to index data, how to secure the data,
如何对数据进行索引，如何保障数据安全，
how to store the data, how to distribute the data efficiently.
如何存储数据，如何高效地分发数据。
And very importantly, how to analyze the data, how to learn from the data.
非常重要的是，如何分析数据，如何从数据中学习。
This is a common theme that goes through many, many of these different areas.
这是贯穿许多不同领域的一个共同主题。
One needs to coordinate the use of computing storage network resources.
需要协调计算存储网络资源的使用。
Which, while they're ample, is still quite limited compared to the scale of the data
尽管资源充足，但与数据规模相比仍然显得相当有限。
and computation tasks that these applications face.
以及这些应用程序面临的计算任务。
Now today, what's happening is, these experts in these various domains
如今，这些不同领域的专家正在处理这些系统问题，往往彼此孤立。
are dealing with these systems problems, often in isolation from each other.
正在处理这些系统问题，往往彼此孤立。
So they've had to develop their own solutions to deal with these problems.
因此，他们不得不开发自己的解决方案来处理这些问题。
And actually, a lot of these efforts are being replicated across these domains.
实际上，这些努力在这些领域中被重复进行。
And one can see a kind of stovepipe
而人们可以看到一种烟囱式
kind of situation across these different domains.
在这些不同领域中可以看到一种类似的情况。
And one might ask, well, why is this happening,
人们可能会问，这是为什么呢？
that these smart people in these different domains all have to develop their own
这些聪明的人在各个不同的领域都必须开发他们自己的
systems to handle all of these problems?
系统来处理所有这些问题吗？
Well, one underlying reason is that there exists this gap
嗯，一个潜在的原因是存在这样一个差距
between the application needs and the existing networks and systems.
在应用需求和现有网络及系统之间。
So the current networks and systems focus on addresses,
因此，当前的网络和系统关注于地址，
processes, servers, connections.
进程、服务器、连接。
And consequently, the security solutions that they have also focus on securing
因此，他们所拥有的安全解决方案也集中于确保安全
data containers and delivery pipes.
数据容器和传输管道。
Whereas the applications actually care about the data.
然而，应用程序实际上关心的是数据。
And so this is a gap, of course, that's been identified
这当然是一个已经被识别出的差距。
also as a primary motivation for things like NDN.
这也是像NDN这样的东西出现的主要动机之一。
But this gap, I think, is one of the primary reasons why you're seeing
但我认为，这种差距是你看到这些系统解决方案在不同领域被复制的主要原因之一。
these systems solutions being replicated across these different domains.
这些系统解决方案在这些不同领域被复制。
And so what we're focusing on is taking a data-centric
我们所关注的是采用以数据为中心的方法来进行系统和网络设计。
approach to systems and network design.
我们采取的方法是系统和网络设计。
And apply this approach to the large-scale data-intensive science area.
并将这种方法应用到大规模数据密集型科学领域。
So this approach, the idea is to provide system
所以这种方法，其理念是提供系统支持贯穿整个数据生命周期。
support through the whole data life cycle.
支持贯穿整个数据生命周期。
From the data production, naming the data,
从数据的产生、命名数据，
securing the data directly, to delivering the data using naming.
从直接保护数据，到使用命名来传递数据。
Therefore enabling scalable data retrieval, enabling in-network caching,
因此实现了可扩展的数据检索，实现了网络内缓存，
automated joint caching, forwarding, multicast delivery.
实现了自动化的联合缓存、转发和多播传递。
We wanna develop a common framework that can support different application domains,
我们希望建立一个通用框架，能够支持不同的应用领域，
and not have to replicate these efforts every time we have a new application.
并且不需要每当我们有新应用时就重复这些努力。
And NDN is something that enables that, and
并且NDN就是实现这一目标的东西，
is in fact a very appropriate architecture for
实际上是一个非常合适的架构来
solving these large data-intensive science areas.
解决这些大型数据密集型科学领域的问题。
So one of the first projects to take this approach is the SANDIE project,
因此，采用这种方法的首批项目之一是SANDIE项目，
SDN-Assisted NDN for Data Intensive Experiments, which started In 2017.
采用SDN辅助的NDN用于数据密集型实验，该项目始于2017年。
So the team consisted of Northeastern headed by myself, Harvey Newman,
因此，这个团队由我自己领导的东北大学和哈维·纽曼组成，
a very influential physicist and networking physicist from Caltech.
一个来自加州理工学院的非常有影响力的物理学家和网络物理学家。
And Christos Papadopoulos from Florida State, and
来自佛罗里达州立大学的克里斯托斯·帕帕多普洛斯，以及
then transitioning to Craig Partridge after Christos went to DHS.
随后在克里斯托斯前往国土安全部之后，由克雷格·帕特里奇接替。
And of course, and in partnership with other LHC sites and the NDN project team.
当然，这还需要与其他LHC站点以及NDN项目团队合作。
The approach of the SANDIE project was to use SDN-assisted NDN to redesign the LHC,
SANDIE项目的方法是利用SDN辅助的NDN来重新设计LHC，
the Large Hadron Collider high energy physics network to optimize the workflow.
大型强子对撞机高能物理网络，以优化工作流程。
We developed an NDN naming scheme for fast access and
我们开发了一个NDN命名方案，用于快速访问和
efficient communication in high energy physics.
我们在高能物理中开发了一种用于高效通信的NDN命名方案。
We deployed NDN edge caches with SSDs in multiple sites.
我们在多个站点部署了带有SSD的NDN边缘缓存。
And we used simultaneous optimization of caching and
我们还同时优化了缓存和转发，以提高数据传输的效率。
forwarding to make the data delivery efficient.
我们还同时优化了转发，以提高数据传输的效率。
Now, this is, of course, we're actually building a real system here.
现在，当然，我们实际上在这里构建一个真实的系统。
So the feasibility of an NDN-based data distribution system for
因此，一个基于NDN的数据分发系统的可行性
LHC was first demonstrated at supercomputing 2018 in Dallas.
LHC首次在2018年达拉斯的超级计算会议上展示。
And last year in Denver at SC 19, we show greatly improved throughput and
去年在丹佛的SC 19会议上，我们展示了大幅提高的吞吐量并且通过利用一些方法改善了延迟性能。
delay performance by leveraging a couple of things.
延迟性能的提升是通过利用一些方法实现的联合优化。
One was the joint optimization of caching and
延迟性能的提升是通过利用一些方法实现的联合优化，其中之一是缓存和转发的联合优化，使用的是由东北大学开发的VIP算法。
forwarding using the VIP algorithm that was developed by Northeastern.
利用东北大学开发的VIP算法进行转发。
We then leveraged the NDN-DPDK forwarder which
我们随后利用了NDN-DPDK转发器，它
Lotfi mentioned was developed by NIST.
Lotfi 提到的是由 NIST 开发的。
And we used an NDN-DPDK-based consumer and
我们使用了基于NDN-DPDK的消费者和
producer developed by Caltech.
我们开发了加州理工学院的生产者。
And then we had a live demo at SC 19 over a transcontinental layer two demo testbed
然后我们在SC 19上进行了一个横跨大陆的二层演示测试床的现场演示。
that was running from the SC 19 floor to Caltech to Northeastern to Colorado State.
这是从SC 19会场直通到加州理工学院，再到东北大学，然后到科罗拉多州立大学的运行路径。
We were able to achieve over 6.7 gigabits per second throughput
我们能够实现超过6.7吉比特每秒的吞吐量。
using a single thread between the NDN-DPDK-based consumer and producer.
使用单个线程在基于NDN-DPDK的消费者和生产者之间进行通信。
And we also showed in another experiment that, using the optimized caching and
我们还在另一个实验中展示了，通过使用优化的缓存和转发算法，
forwarding algorithms,
转发算法，
we were able to decrease download times by a factor of ten.
我们能够将下载时间缩短到原来的十分之一。
So that was a very exciting demo that we had last year.
所以那是我们去年非常激动人心的一个演示。
And this is a picture of the throughput that we obtained.
这是我们获得的吞吐量的图片。
You can see on the upper left-hand corner there,
您可以看到左上角那里，
the 6.71 gigabits per second throughput.
6.71吉比特每秒的吞吐量。
And by the way, assessment was very
顺便说一句，评估非常~!@#$%^&*()
much a part of that demo that we had last year in Denver.
那是我们去年在丹佛进行的演示的一部分。
Now what is the latest development this year?
那么今年最新的发展是什么？
NSF has just awarded a new project called N-DISE.
美国国家科学基金会刚刚资助了一个名为N-DISE的新项目。
N-DISE stands for NDN for Data Intensive Science Experiments.
N-DISE代表面向数据密集型科学实验的NDN。
This is gonna start this year, and in some sense,
这将于今年开始，从某种意义上来讲，
this is a continuation of the SANDIE project,
这是SANDIE项目的延续，
a much expanded version headed by Northeastern, myself.
这是一个由东北大学和我本人领导的大幅扩展版本。
And participating co-PIs, Harvey Newman,
以及参与的联合主持人，Harvey Newman，
Lixia Zhang from UCLA, Jason Cong from UCLA, and
Lixia Zhang 来自加州大学洛杉矶分校，Jason Cong 也来自加州大学洛杉矶分校，以及参与的联合主持人，Harvey Newman，Susmit Shannigrahi 来自田纳西科技大学。
Susmit Shannigrahi from Tennessee Tech.
Susmit Shannigrahi 来自田纳西科技大学。
In partnership with LHC, and other genomics collaborators such as
与LHC以及其他基因组学合作者如 Alex Feltus 刚才发言的，以及NDN项目团队合作。
Alex Feltus, who just spoke, and the NDN project team.
与刚才发言的Alex Feltus以及NDN项目团队合作。
So the challenges for N-DISE, we had SANDIE for the last three years.
因此，对于N-DISE的挑战，我们在过去三年里有了SANDIE。
But LHC, the data volume is gonna grow by another ten times due
但是LHC的数据量将因此增长十倍。
to the high luminosity LHC experiment starting in 2027.
将在2027年开始的高亮度LHC实验。
It's gonna be much increased data complexity, human genome data,
将会有大幅度增加的数据复杂性，人类基因组数据，
Earth biogenome data, is going into the exabyte range.
地球生物基因组数据，即将进入艾字节量级。
So that's a part of this N-DISE project as well.
这也是N-DISE项目的一部分。
There's a need to use diverse computation, storage, network, resources.
需要使用多样化的计算、存储、网络资源。
And our approach is to build a data-centric ecosystem to provide agile,
我们的方法是构建一个以数据为中心的生态系统，以提供敏捷的、
integrated, interoperable, scalable, robust, and trustworthy solutions for
集成的、互操作的、可扩展的、稳健的、可信赖的解决方案，用于
heterogeneous data-intensive domains in the manner that
异构数据密集型领域中的方式，正如我在演讲中早些时候所描述的。
I described earlier in the talk.
我在演讲中早些时候所描述的。
So the goal of N-DISE is to deploy and condition the first prototype
因此，N-DISE的目标是部署并配置第一个原型
production-ready NDN-based petascale data distribution, caching,
生产就绪的基于NDN的千万亿字节级数据分发、缓存、
access, and computation system serving major science programs.
生产就绪的基于NDN的千万亿字节级数据分发、缓存、访问和计算系统，服务于主要科学计划。
The LHC high energy physics program will be a leading target use case.
LHC高能物理计划将成为主要的目标应用案例。
But the other application we'll be focusing on is the BioGenome,
但我们将重点关注的另一个应用是生物基因组项目，
human genome projects And as future use cases we'll be looking at LSST, SKA.
人类基因组项目。至于未来的用例，我们将关注LSST（大型综合巡天望远镜）和SKA（方尖碑阵列射电望远镜）。
We'll leverage NDN protocols, high throughput forwarding caching techniques,
我们将利用NDN协议，高吞吐量的转发缓存技术，
containerization techniques, as Alex was talking about in order to handle different
容器化技术，正如Alex所讨论的，为了处理不同的
operating systems to be able to upgrade easily.
操作系统能够轻松升级。
Integrated with SDN techniques and as well as FPGA acceleration subsystems.
集成了SDN技术以及FPGA加速子系统。
So Jason Tong is an FPGA expert that's on the team.
所以Jason Tong是团队中的FPGA专家。
We're aiming to deliver LHC data over wide area network at throughputs near 100
我们的目标是通过广域网传输LHC数据，吞吐量接近每秒100千兆比特。
gigabits per second.
千兆比特每秒。
That'll be our target achievable because of when we use, we're planning to do multi
我们的目标是可以实现的，因为当我们使用时，我们计划进行多线程实现，这将允许吞吐量线性扩展。
threaded implementations which is going to allow for linear scaling of throughput.
多线程实现，这将允许吞吐量线性扩展。
We'll be looking at dramatically decreasing download times by using
我们将通过使用来显著缩短下载时间。
optimized caching.
我们将通过使用优化缓存来显著缩短下载时间。
And we'll have built an enhanced testbed with high performance
我们将构建一个具有高性能的增强型测试平台。
NDN data cache servers.
NDN数据缓存服务器。
So how much time do I have left to spend?
我还剩多少时间可以使用？
>> About five minutes.
>> 大约五分钟。
>> Okay, good.
>> 好的，很好。
So to go into the research agenda a bit more in detail.
所以，让我们更详细地深入研究议程。
So we had built the NBN-DPDK consumer and producer Caltech had done that.
因此，我们已经构建了NBN-DPDK消费者和生产者，是加州理工学院完成的。
We're now going to look at developing multi threaded consumer and
我们现在将研究开发多线程消费者和
producer applications to aim for linear throughput scaling.
我们现在将研究开发多线程消费者和生产者应用程序，以实现线性吞吐量扩展。This is going to be integrated with a NDN-DPDK, XRootD plugin.
This is going to be integrated with a NDN-DPDK, XRootD plugin.
这将与NDN-DPDK、XRootD插件集成。
XRootD is the current redirector tool application that's used in LHC in
XRootD是目前在LHC中使用的重定向工具应用程序。
order for people to discover data and to map requests to different servers.
为了让人们发现数据并将请求映射到不同的服务器。
And so what we previously did in Sandy was to build a plugin that
为了让人们发现数据并将请求映射到不同的服务器，我们之前在Sandy做的是构建了一个插件，它允许你与一个NDN网络系统接口。
allowed you to interface with an NDN networking system.
允许你与一个NDN网络系统接口。
And so this has actually been developed or now integrated with NDN-DPDK.
于是，这实际上已被开发或现在与NDN-DPDK集成在一起了。
And now we're going to integrate that with a multi threaded consumer producer
现在我们将要将其与多线程的消费者生产者进行集成。
application.
现在我们将要将其与多线程的消费者生产者进行集成。我们将要研究用于NDN-DPDK的容器以及应用程序。
We're going to be looking at containers for NDN-DPDK and
我们将要研究用于NDN-DPDK的容器以及
other applications in order to handle diverse server requirements,
其他应用程序以处理多样化的服务器需求，
server equipment and interfaces.
服务器设备和接口。
We're looking at using docker containers so that we can host guest
我们正在考虑使用Docker容器，这样我们就可以托管客户端操作系统，便于状态恢复，方便升级。
operating systems, enables easy state restoration, ease upgrading.
操作系统，便于状态恢复，方便升级。
We'll be looking at data integrity and provenance.
我们将会研究数据的完整性和来源。
This is we want to do data origin authentication.
我们想要进行数据来源验证。
So even though maybe security is not a huge concern in let's say LHC data,
所以即使在比如说LHC数据中，安全可能不是一个巨大的担忧，
authentication is a huge concern.
鉴权是一个巨大的关注点。
Not only do we want to authenticate to data origin, but
我们不仅想对数据来源进行鉴权，而且
we wanna authenticate, we want to do authenticated traces.
我们想进行认证，我们想做经过认证的追踪。
Because what happens in these applications is that the output data from one
因为在这些应用程序中发生的情况是，一个应用程序的输出数据将作为另一个科学家小组的输入数据用于其他研究科学家。
group of scientists is going to be used as input data for other research scientists.
一组科学家的输出数据将作为其他研究科学家的输入数据。
So we want to authenticate, we want to do authenticated tracing as the data moves
因此，我们希望进行身份验证，我们想要在数据移动时进行认证追踪。
through a multiple processing steps.
因此，它会经过多个处理步骤。
So this will be extremely valuable for data scientists in this area.
因此，这对这一领域的数据科学家来说将是极其宝贵的。
And we're aiming to do this through data manifests where you compute hashes of data
我们的目标是通过数据清单来实现这一点，在数据清单中，你会计算数据的哈希值。
segments and then you sign the hashes.
段落，然后你对哈希值进行签名。
We want to do congestion control retransmission using something called
我们想要使用一种称为NETBLT的东西来进行拥塞控制重传。
NETBLT.
NETBLT（网络块传输）。
Which, I think, developed many years ago, but we're gonna put it
它是很多年前开发的，但我们打算要实施它。
at the network layer so that we can effectively interface with caching.
在网络层面上，这样我们就可以有效地与缓存系统进行交互。
We're gonna be looking at advanced caching storage solutions.
我们将会研究高级缓存存储解决方案。
So we want to extend the VIP caching forwarding
因此我们想要扩展VIP缓存转发功能。
algorithm to interact with multi threaded borders.
算法与多线程边界进行交互。
We're going to look at hierarchical caching systems involving different types
我们将研究涉及不同类型的分层缓存系统。
of memory SSDs, Intel Optane for handling large data volumes.
我们将研究涉及不同类型的分层缓存系统，如内存SSDs、用于处理大数据量的Intel Optane。So in these applications,
So in these applications,
所以在这些应用程序中，
the volume is still huge that one has to exploit all kinds of
存储空间，并且这需要一个分层的缓存系统。
We want to use FPGA acceleration with so FPGA is known to be programming adaptive,
我们想要使用FPGA加速，因为FPGA是众所周知的可编程自适应的，
it can give us a high throughput, low latency energy efficiency.
它可以为我们提供高吞吐量、低延迟和高能效。
The primary focus here will be to use FPGA acceleration to accelerate hash functions,
这里的主要焦点将是使用FPGA加速来加速哈希函数，
lookups in the NDN-DPDK Name Dispatch Table,
在NDN-DPDK名称调度表中进行查找，
the PIT-CS Composite Table and also the FIB.
在NDN-DPDK名称调度表中进行查找，包括PIT-CS复合表以及FIB。So, to wrap up the talk, data-intensive science applications such as LHC,
So, to wrap up the talk, so data intensive science applications such as LHC,
因此，总结一下，像LHC这样的数据密集型科学应用，
Genomics and various other applications require fundamental
基因组学和其他各种应用需要基础的
network system solutions to address common needs.
网络系统解决方案以满足共同需求。
NDN provides such a common framework that data-centric
NDN提供了这样一个以数据为中心的通用框架，
systems support that provides support through the whole data lifecycle.
系统支持提供了贯穿整个数据生命周期的支持。
It's a natural fit for applications like LHC, genomics and
它自然适合于应用程序，如大型强子对撞机(LHC)、基因组学和其他数据密集型应用。
other data intensive applications.
其他数据密集型应用。
We've already shown in the SANDIE project that we can get
我们已经在SANDIE项目中展示了我们可以获得其他数据密集型应用非常高性能的NDN。
very high performance with NDN.
我们可以获得非常高性能的NDN。
We should have throughput at 6.7 gigabits per second over wide area network
我们应该能在广域网上实现每秒6.7吉比特的吞吐量。
using NDN-DPDK forwarder using the optimized caching voting algorithms.
利用优化的缓存投票算法的NDN-DPDK转发器。
So the point is that we can get very high performance using
所以重点是我们可以通过使用获得非常高的性能
NDN approach to large scale data intensive science.
NDN方法用于大规模数据密集型科学。
And the new project N-DISE, we're working toward the first prototype,
我们正在努力开发新项目N-DISE的第一个原型，
production ready NDN system, which is going to be integrated with SDN,
生产就绪的NDN系统，它将与SDN集成。
with FPGA and containerization.
与FPGA和容器化技术相结合。
And of course, we're seeking long-term collaboration with various domain
当然，我们正在寻求与各个领域的科学家、网络计算机系统社区长期合作，以便推动这一进程。
scientists, networking computer system communities in order to push forward this
我们正在与科学家、网络计算机系统社区合作，以推动这一进程。
project to build data-centric ecosystems for large scale data intensive science.
项目旨在为大规模数据密集型科学构建以数据为中心的生态系统。
Thanks very much.
非常感谢。
>> Thank you Edmund.
>> 非常感谢，埃德蒙。
I think Dave has a question for you or a comment.
我认为戴夫对你有一个问题或者想发表评论。
>> Am I muted?
>> 我被静音了吗？
>> No, we can hear you.
>> 不，我们能听见你。
>> Good, so you're calling something tracing.
>> 好的，所以你们称之为追踪。
Which I've always heard called Data provenance.
我一直听说这被称作数据溯源。
I'm curious if you think of it as something different or
我好奇你是否认为它是一种不同的东西。
is this the same stuff that Margo Seltzer and
她和Margo Seltzer以及她的合作者们已经研究了10年的东西吗？
her collaborators have been working on for 10 years.
她的合作者们已经研究了10年的东西。
>> So I'm actually not aware of that to admit what you said but
所以实际上我并不了解，无法承认你所说的内容。
the idea here is to basically,
基本上的想法是要……
essentially do a multistep provenance cell.
本质上是要做一个多步骤的起源追踪细胞。
>> Yeah, right, right, right, right.
>> 是的，对，对，对。
>> So. >> There's like 10 years of
>> 是的。>> 大约有10年的
papers on this.
这方面的论文。
I think you people should look at it before you go invent something new.
我认为在你们尝试发明新东西之前，你们应该先看看这方面的论文。
>> Yeah, I didn't really actually mean to suggest necessarily it's a new thing.
是的，我并不是真的想要暗示这是一个全新的事物。
But we're just going to do that in the context of large scale data intensive
但我们将在大规模数据密集型的背景下进行这项工作。
science, I guess and within this ecosystem.
科学，我猜，以及在这个生态系统之内。
>> That is really useful to talk to Margo about this.
这真的很有用，可以和Margo谈谈这个问题。
She's known at UBC because when I heard her last talk, she basically said,
她在UBC很有名，因为我听她上一次演讲时，她基本上说，
yeah, we know, pretty much understand how to do all this.
是的，我们知道，基本上明白如何去做这一切。
The technical means of doing with multi signatures and
多重签名的技术手段以及
backward pointers and stuff like that.
向后指针之类的东西。
You know, we sorta know how to do it.
你知道，我们有点知道怎么做了。
What happened was when we tried to do this, the scientists hated it.
发生的事情是，当我们尝试去做这件事时，科学家们非常反感。
>> Okay.
好的。
>> So figuring out how to get the scientists on board with a data provenance
那么，搞清楚如何让科学家们接受使用NDN下的数据溯源系统可能比他们在其他系统中发现的要容易。
system under NDN might be easier than what they've discovered with other systems.
因此，在NDN下的系统中，搞清楚如何让科学家们接受使用数据溯源系统可能比他们在其他系统中发现的要容易。
>> Right.
对。
That's a good I mean, so you know, security and provinance has not been so
这是一个很好的，我是说，所以你知道，安全性和来源迄今为止还没有成为
far a major concern in the physics community just because I think that they
他们在物理学界尚未将其视为一个主要的担忧，仅仅是因为我认为他们
Control access to their network very tightly.
他们对他们的网络访问进行了非常严格的控制。
At the moment, so maybe they don't worry about it.
目前，他们可能并不担心这个问题。
But I think in at least in other data intensive areas.
但我认为至少在其他数据密集型领域。
>> Our environment really, important.
>> 我们的环境确实非常重要。
>> Yeah.
>> 是的。
>> Right. >> So we will have but yeah,
>> 对。>> 所以我们会有，但是是的，
they probably they will need some convincing.
他们可能需要一些说服。
Yes, and that effort is just starting.
是的，而且这项努力才刚刚开始。
So we'll know.
所以我们会知道。
>> All I'm saying is that, anybody who's actually doing the technical
所以我们会知道。任何真正在做技术工作以开发追踪算法的人，朋友Deanne。
What a review of the literature on data provenance.
一篇关于数据溯源的文献综述。
>> Okay, yeah.
好的。
Thank you, thanks for pointing that out.
谢谢，感谢你指出那一点。
>> Thanks.
谢谢。
>> Alright, thank you Edmund.
好的，谢谢你埃德蒙。
Flip the, flip the >> Next subject.
翻转，翻转 >> 下一个话题。
>> Our next speaker is Lan Wang.
>> 我们的下一个演讲者是王兰。
Lan is gonna be a professor and
王兰将成为一名教授，并且是孟菲斯大学计算机科学系主任。
So, you will be speaking about M card,
那么，你将会谈论M卡，
secure, real time data distribution system,
安全的、实时的数据分发系统，
with fine grain access control for, M health research,
具有细粒度访问控制的，用于M健康研究，
the continuation of the discussion that we just had, planned.
我们刚才讨论的内容的继续，已经计划好了。
>> Yes, but how do I share?
是的，但我该如何分享呢？
I think admin needs to stop sharing.
我认为管理员需要停止分享。
>> Even start sharing just put you can push them out if you start yours.
>> 即使开始共享，如果你开始你的，你也可以将它们推出去。
>> Okay, See my screen
>> 好的，看我的屏幕
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> Okay, good morning.
>> 好的，早上好。
I'm going to talk about a new initiative funded project mGuard.
我将要讲述一个新的资助项目mGuard。
This is a collaboration between me,
这是我与其他人的合作，
my colleague Santosh Kumar and Lixia Zhang at UCLA.
这是我与我的同事桑托什·库马尔和加州大学洛杉矶分校的张丽霞的合作。
Today, many of us have smartwatches, smartphones, smart scales.
如今，我们中的许多人都有智能手表、智能手机、智能秤。
These devices monitor our heart rate, blood oxygen levels,
这些设备监测我们的心率、血氧水平、
sleep, weight, and various other biometrics.
睡眠、体重以及其他各种生物识别数据。
Such mobile health data, it can be used to
这些移动健康数据可以用来
study a wide range of health and wellness issues, such as stress,
研究各种健康和健康问题，例如压力、
sleep disorders, congestive heart failures, and migraine.
睡眠障碍、充血性心力衰竭和偏头疼。
But the data reveals a lot of our own private lives.
但这些数据揭露了我们很多个人隐私。
So the privacy and security issues here,
所以这里的隐私和安全问题，
need to be investigated.
需要被调查。
But existing mobile health data infrastructure
但现有的移动健康数据基础设施
lack support for fine-grained access control.
缺乏对细粒度访问控制的支持。
For example, you can get access to a whole data set.
例如，您可以获得整个数据集的访问权限。
But you can they cannot control which users data you
但是你可以控制他们无法控制哪些用户的数据。
can look at which users data you cannot, they can also,
无法查看哪些用户的数据，他们也可以，
they cannot enforce Access Control based on time or location either.
他们也无法基于时间或地点执行访问控制。
So that is a big constraint.
所以这是一个很大的限制。
Also, researchers cannot get real time
因此，研究人员无法实时获得
many times, they cannot get real time access to the data.
很多时候，他们无法实时获取数据。
They are only send the data after everything is collected.
他们只有在数据全部收集完毕后才发送数据。
But if you want to do real time intervention,
但如果你想进行实时干预，
then that's not feasible with current access.
那么用当前的访问方式是不可行的。
So we want to apply NDN's name based data centric approach to solve these problems.
因此，我们希望应用NDN的基于名称的数据中心方法来解决这些问题。
And because here we have
所以在这里我们有
NIH funded mobile health data center.
美国国立卫生研究院资助的移动健康数据中心。
So it's very natural for us to collaborate with this
所以我们与之合作是很自然的事情。
NIH MD2K centre to work on this problem.
美国国立卫生研究院MD2K中心致力于研究这个问题。
So MD2K stands for mobile sensor data to knowledge.
所以MD2K代表的是从移动传感器数据到知识。
It is one of 11 National NIH big data centres of excellence.
它是美国国立卫生研究院11个大数据卓越中心之一。
It's led by my colleague Santosh Kumar.
它是由我的同事Santosh Kumar领导的。
Their mission is to develop tools, to gather, analyze,
他们的使命是开发工具，来收集、分析，
and interpret health data generated by mobile and wearable sensors.
和解释由移动和可穿戴传感器生成的健康数据。
The, MD2K center, is a collaboration amongst
MD2K中心是由多方合作组成的联盟，包括
17 universities involving many faculty members,
17所大学涉及许多教职员工，
students and staff members.
学生和教职员工。
So they conduct many health related studies.
因此，他们进行了许多与健康相关的研究。
And the studies produce a lot of sensor data and
因此，研究产生了大量的传感器数据，
all the data is collected by the MD2K's enter,
therefore, the research has generated a large amount of sensor data, which is then uploaded into a cloud based system.
into a cloud based system.
上传到一个基于云的系统中。
And through the system, the study coordinators can
通过该系统，研究协调员可以实时监控他们的参与者。
monitor their participants in real time.
研究协调员可以实时监控他们的参与者。
The data science researchers can use the data to develop bile markers and
数据科学研究人员可以利用数据来开发胆汁标记物并且验证这些标记物。
validate the markers.
验证这些标记物。
And then the health researchers,
然后是健康研究人员，
can you use the bile markers to analyze their patients' health,
能否利用胆汁标志物来分析他们病人的健康状况，
and study the effectiveness of the bile markers.
并研究胆汁标志物的有效性。
This data has more than 2200 participants.
这些数据有2200多名参与者。
More than 100,000 participant days.
超过10万名参与者的天数。
4.7 trillion data points and more than 300 terabytes of data size.
4.7万亿个数据点和超过300TB的数据大小。
These numbers are from last year.
这些数字是去年的数据。
Probably the current data size is much bigger.
可能当前的数据量要大得多。
So, here's the proposed mGuard system.
所以，这就是我们提出的mGuard系统。
We don't want to change the existing system, we want to enhance it.
我们不想改变现有的系统，我们想要增强它。
So, we will continue to use the existing MD2K components.
所以，我们将继续使用现有的MD2K组件。
There are two major components.
因此，我们将继续使用现有的MD2K组件。其中一个叫做M小脑？
One is called M cerebellum?
一个叫做M小脑？
It's a data collection platform composed of sensors and
它是一个由传感器和移动电话组成的数据收集平台，用于收集研究参与者的数据。
mobile phones to collect data from study participants.
移动电话用于收集研究参与者的数据。
And this platform will send data to cerebral cortex.
这个平台将数据发送到大脑皮层。
That's a cloud based system to store and support computing on the data.
这是一个基于云的系统，用于存储数据并支持数据计算。
And what we are going to do is to add an NDN data adapter that
将在NDN格式中加密、签名并打包数据。
And store the packets in MDN repo.
并将数据包存储在MDN仓库中。
And these two systems, sorry these two components will work on
并且这两个系统，抱歉，这两个组件将会运作在
top of NDN forwarder to send and receive NDN packets.
这两个组件将会运作在NDN转发器的顶层来发送和接收NDN数据包。
That's on the server side, on the receiver side, the users can continue to use
在接收端，用户可以继续使用
their legacy applications, or their existing applications.
他们的遗留应用程序，或者他们现有的应用程序。
But we will develop new Indian based research
但我们将开展基于印度的新研究。
application that can subscribe to the data from
应用程序可以订阅来自数据的
the server and then >> I mean,
服务器然后 >> 我的意思是，
decrypt to the data and verify the data and
解密数据并验证数据
then store the data in a database that can be used by the existing application.
然后将数据存储在现有应用程序可以使用的数据库中。
And we will also have an NDN data consumer that
我们还将拥有一个NDN（命名数据网络）数据消费者，它
will perform the substance corruption and
将执行数据破坏和
publication activities and also send and
出版活动以及发送和
receive data, sorry, interest and data packets.
接收数据、抱歉、兴趣和数据包。
So this overall enhanced system will provide the fine
-grained data access control capability and 所以这个全面增强的系统将提供细粒度的数据访问控制能力和
grained data access control capability and
细粒度的数据访问控制能力和
also real-time data distribution capability.
还具备实时数据分发能力。
Here's the proposed naming structure for the system.
这是系统命名结构的建议方案。
This is strictly directly from the proposal.
这是直接来自提案的内容。
We still need to refine it.
我们仍需要对其进行完善。
So we have the data organization name as
我们有数据组织名称为
the root prefix and then under that we have different studies.
我们有不同的研究下属于该根前缀。
And for each study, depending on what kind of data they collect,
对于每项研究，根据它们收集的数据类型，
the each type of data is the branch under that study.
每种数据类型都是那项研究下的一个分支。
And then we have more finer grain, data type and user ID.
然后我们有了更细粒度的数据类型和用户ID。
And then below the user, we have a branch for
接着在用户下面，我们有一个分支用于
the actual data and the encryption key.
实际数据和加密密钥。
We also have branch for access control to encrypt
我们还有一个用于访问控制加密的分支。
the content key and decrypt the content key.
内容密钥和解密内容密钥。
So these are used by the producers and consumers of the data.
因此，这些被数据的生产者和消费者所使用。
That's the overall naming scheme and we also have a trust model.
这是整体的命名方案，我们还有一个信任模型。
This is a preliminary model.
这是一个初步模型。
It also needs to be refined.
它还需要进一步完善。
At the top level, we have the overall md2k organizations trust,
在最顶层，我们有整个md2k组织的信任，
anchor T which signs each research studies key and
位于最顶层的T锚点，将签署每项研究的关键数据。
each research study is key will sign their data.
每项研究的关键数据将由其签署。
So that's how you authenticate the data produced by
因此，这就是你验证由特定用户从特定研究中产生的数据的方式。
a particular user from a particular study.
特定用户从特定研究中。
Everything will be traced back to the trust anchor key which is the empty
一切将追溯到信任锚定密钥，即为空的密钥。
two-key organizations key and we have developed a preliminary schemas for
两把组织密钥，我们已经为其开发了一个初步的模式。
validating the keys, and the data.
验证密钥和数据。
And how do we support the real time data distribution and access control?
我们如何支持实时数据分发和访问控制？
We will continue to use the existing
我们将继续使用现有的
NDN libraries and code.
NDN库和代码。
For the subscription to the data,
为了订阅数据，
we will use the PSync library which has a Pub/Sub API
我们将使用具有发布/订阅 API 的 PSync 库来实现这一功能。
to discover and subscribe to data streams.
为了发现并订阅数据流。
And then the producers are here is actually just
然后这里的生产者实际上只是
the md2k center after they have collected the data,
在他们收集了数据之后，MD2K中心会使用基于名称的访问控制方案来保护数据。
they will use the name based access control scheme to protect the data.
他们将使用基于名称的访问控制方案来保护数据。
The data is encrypted based on the access control policies.
数据根据访问控制策略进行了加密。
Here we need to develop a schema to specify these access control policies.
我们需要开发一个模式来指定这些访问控制策略。
Here is just an example.
这只是一个例子。
For example, the users who are allowed to access the data,
例如，被允许访问数据的用户，
here you can specify which data set the user is allowed to access.
在这里，您可以指定用户被允许访问哪些数据集。
And the user is only allowed to access a user's data if
用户只有在以下情况下才被允许访问用户的数据：如果
the timestamp is between 9 AM and 6 PM, and
时间戳是在上午9点到下午6点之间，且
the location is in this person's office, and
the location is in this person's office, and the permission is to read not to write the data.
the permission is to read not to write the data.
权限是读取数据而不是写入数据。
So we will develop this kind of schema to specify the access control policies and
因此，我们将开发这种模式来指定访问控制策略，以及
then the library will be used to automatically
那么这个库将被用来自动
generate the keys to site to encrypt and sign the data.
生成密钥以对网站数据进行加密和签名。
And then use the next scheme to distribute
然后使用下一个方案来分发
the key encryption and decryption keys.
加密和解密的关键密钥。
>> Have about another minute.
>> 大约还有一分钟。
>> Okay, so in this past summer, we have developed a next scheme
>> 好的，因此在这个过去的夏天，我们已经开发出了一个新方案
that can enforce policies that have spatial and temporal attributes.
可以强制执行具有空间和时间属性的策略。
For example, you can specify the time interval and the location of the user and
例如，您可以指定用户的时间间隔和位置，以及
my student launching will present this particular scheme tomorrow.
我的学生明天将展示这个特定的计划。
This is the last slide.
这是最后一张幻灯片。
The project hasn't started yet.
项目还没有开始。
It will officially start next month.
它将在下个月正式开始。
And when the system is ready,
并且当系统准备就绪时，
we plan to do a trial deployment over the NDN test bed,
我们计划在NDN测试床上进行试验部署，
so that researchers can connect to the test bed and
以便研究人员能够连接到测试床并且
receive the data in real-time.
接收实时数据。
And this, we have a team composed of me and the three students from my group.
我们有一个团队，由我和我的小组里的三名学生组成。
Santosh Kumar and Nasir Ali who is a research assistant
Santosh Kumar和研究助理Nasir Ali。
professor in my department, and Lixia and two of her students.
我系的教授，还有Lixia和她的两名学生。
The website is at mguarded.md2k.org.
网站地址是 mguarded.md2k.org。
That's for the presentation.
这是用于演示的。
>> Thank you, Lan.
>> 谢谢，兰。
Are there any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Think we have time for this one?
我们有时间做这个吗？
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
Hey, hear me?
嘿，你能听见我吗？
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> Hi, this is a Ageque from Canada.
>> 嗨，我是来自加拿大的Ageque。
I want to ask the professor plan one is have
我想问教授计划一是有什么。
you ever considered combined NDN with
您是否曾考虑过将NDN与~!@#$%^&*()结合起来？
the IPMFS all together to do the same thing?
您是否曾考虑过将IPMFS全部结合起来做同一件事？
>> We actually discussed internally
我们实际上已经在内部讨论过了。
about IPFS a while back.
我们之前讨论过IPFS。
So I think they're trying to do what NDN is trying to achieve,
所以我认为他们试图实现的是NDN所努力达成的目标，
but at a higher level at the application level and being a network layer.
但是在更高的层面上，在应用层面，同时也是网络层。
Being an architecture that starts from the network layer,
作为从网络层开始的架构，
I think NDN has some advantages over IPFS.
我认为NDN相比于IPFS有一些优势。
So I think for this project,
所以我认为对于这个项目来说，
we we are not going to try to use IPFS.
所以我认为对于这个项目来说，我们不打算尝试使用IPFS。But because NDN already provides the capabilities
But because NDN already provides the capabilities
但因为NDN已经提供了这些能力
of what IPFS track is trying to achieve.
IPFS追求的目标。
At least for this particular project, we can just directly use NDN.
至少对于这个特定的项目，我们可以直接使用NDN。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> Yeah, well, it just is the I would stand for file.
>> 是的，这里的“I”代表文件。
So therefore I think ipfs handles the file objects
所以因此我认为IPFS处理文件对象。
as opposed to hear more generic data objects.
相对于处理更通用的数据对象来说。
It's a kind of design the into the system as opposed
它是一种设计，与其说是反对系统内置的设计。
to running an overlay on top of underlying delivery substrate.
它是在底层交付基础设施之上运行的一个覆盖层。
>> Okay, so thank you Lamb, very nice presentation.
>> 好的，非常感谢Lamb，非常精彩的演讲。
The last talk of the session is.
本次会议的最后一场演讲是。
From Ilya Balding, he is the director for network research and
Ilya Balding，他是网络研究和Renzi基础设施的负责人。
infrastructure at Renzi.
他在Renzi的基础设施建设中发挥了主导作用。
He has played a leading leading role in deploying EXA Genie and
他在部署EXA Genie方面发挥了主导作用。
then now he is the lead bi for fabric.
他现在是面料领域的主要商业智能负责人。
He's going to share with us a talk on fabric scan capabilities and use cases.
他将与我们分享一场关于面料扫描能力和使用案例的讲座。
>> Ilya can you share your screen please.
>> 伊利亚，你能分享一下你的屏幕吗？
>> Susmit, I think Ilya is having trouble connecting,
>> 苏斯米特，我觉得伊利亚连接时遇到了问题，
okay, replied to his email with the phone number to dial in instead.
好的，我已经回复了他的电子邮件，并提供了电话号码以供拨入。
I don't know what are you able to do so in time.
我不知道你是否能够及时做到这一点。
>> Do you want me to share the slides?
>> 你希望我分享幻灯片吗？
>> If he does dialing.
>> 如果他拨打电话。
I gave him the number the blue jeans dialing number.
我给了他蓝色牛仔裤的拨号号码。
>> Okay. Just a minute.
>> 好的，稍等一会儿。
>> Let me get it ready in case he can join, but
如果他能加入，我先准备好，不过
if you want to move it to another session, that's fine.
如果你想把它移到另一个环节，那也可以。
>> We can probably start the panel and if he shows up,
我们可能会先开始小组讨论，如果他出现了，
we give him an opportunity after the panel.
我们在小组讨论后给他一个机会。
>> Thank you.
>> 谢谢。
>> Thank you Susmit and all the presenters.
>> 谢谢Susmit和所有的演讲者。
Christos, are you ready?
Christos，你准备好了吗？
>> Yes, I am here.
>> 是的，我在这里。
>> All right.
>> 好的。
Thank you, everybody.
谢谢大家。
So we're moving on to the automotive panel and
所以我们现在转向汽车论坛环节，
a pleasure to welcome the three panelists on the automotive panel.
很高兴欢迎三位小组成员加入汽车论坛。
Mike Westra from Ford, Ted Guild from MIT and W3C and Tao Zhang from NIST,
迈克·韦斯特拉来自福特公司，泰德·吉尔德来自麻省理工学院和W3C，张涛来自美国国家标准技术研究院。
this is gonna be a slightly different panel, we don't have any slides.
这将会是一个有些不同的小组讨论，我们没有任何幻灯片。
And I think that's the right approach for a panel on automotive
我认为这是讨论汽车专题小组的正确方式。
networking which seems to be fairly new, very new rather in the Indian community.
网络联络在印度社区中似乎是相当新的，确切地说是非常新的。
So, we will have about ten minute introductions from each of the panelists
那么，我们将有大约十分钟的时间来听取每位小组成员的介绍。
and then we will devote the time to taking questions from the audience and
之后，我们将抽出时间来回答观众的提问。
even give you an opportunity for the panelists to ask questions to each other.
之后，我们还将为小组成员提供互相提问的机会。
I am very excited about automotive networking.
我对车联网非常感兴趣。
To me, it seems that it's a new frontier in networking.
对我来说，这似乎是网络领域的一个新前沿。
And with this panel, I think it's a great opportunity to hear from people
这个小组讨论，我认为是一个很好的机会去听取那些深入汽车行业领域的人们对于数据的看法。
who are deep into the automotive world industry, data.
深入汽车世界行业的人们，数据。
Sharing and standards and so forth and also new types of uses for
共享与标准等，以及新型用途
smart and connected vehicles, including remote controlled cars.
智能且互联的汽车，包括遥控汽车。
The automotive networks are unique.
汽车网络是独一无二的。
They do combine pretty much everything that we've done as networking researchers.
它们实际上结合了我们作为网络研究者所做的所有事情。
So there is large data coming out of multiple cameras in cars.
所以有大量数据来自汽车上的多个摄像头。
And from HD cameras and lighters.
还有来自高清摄像头和激光雷达的数据。
There's real time requirements.
有实时的要求。
Obviously, there's a lot of heterogeneous communication between different
显然，不同组件之间存在大量异构通信。
components.
组件。
There's aspects of IOT given all the various ECU and
物联网的方面涉及到所有不同的电子控制单元（ECU）和
other sensors that are in a car.
其他传感器都在汽车中。
But it also goes through areas such as cloud computing,
但它也涉及到云计算等领域，
where telematics is being collected.
在此收集了车联网数据。
There's edge computing where data has been processed for video x communication.
这里有边缘计算，数据已经被处理用于视频x通信。
There's a lot of security and privacy issues and of course
还有很多安全和隐私问题，当然
on top of all of that, the industry has to deal with cars that can be on the road for
除了这些之外，该行业还必须处理可以在道路上行驶的汽车，
the next ten twenty years and potentially support these cars and
在接下来的十到二十年里，可能会支持这些汽车并且
keep them up to date for the safety and cyber security and so forth.
保持它们在安全性和网络安全等方面的最新状态。
So, pretty tall order for the automotive industry in this regard.
因此，在这方面汽车工业的任务相当艰巨。
The other challenge comes from telematics or the data that comes from cars.
另一个挑战来自于车联网，或者说是来自汽车的数据。
We've heard the expression there are sensors on wheels.
我们听说过这样一种说法：车轮上装有传感器。
And all these data has great potential to benefit the drivers in terms of
车辆数据具有巨大的潜力，可以在以下方面为驾驶员带来好处：
maintenance, in terms of safety.
在监测车辆是否有入侵以及维护方面，在安全性方面。
providing cybersecurity, but also other users such as the insurance company,
提供网络安全，同时也服务于其他用户，比如保险公司，
who would love to have these data to create better insurance models and
希望利用这些数据来创建更好的保险模型，并希望通过降低利率帮助我们其他人。
hopefully help the rest of us with reduced interest rates.
希望通过降低利率帮助我们其他人。
The data can also benefit society.
数据也可以惠及社会。
We've seen cases with connected cars,
我们已经看到了有关联网汽车的案例，
where the cars in front of you alert the cars behind them for
我们已经看到了有关联网汽车的案例，在这种情况下，前方的车辆会提醒后面的车辆，以避免可能的危险并使道路对其他所有人更加安全。
hazards and making the road safer for everybody else.
障碍物，并使道路对其他所有人更加安全。
But of course with all the data come big issues in privacy, data ownership and
但当然，随着所有这些数据的到来，也带来了隐私、数据所有权等方面的重大问题，
so forth.
等等。
And finally as we're moving into level four, level five autonomous vehicles, and
最后，随着我们进入四级、五级自动驾驶汽车领域，
as we are working on societal acceptance and driver acceptance and so forth,
在我们致力于社会接受度和驾驶员接受度等方面的工作时，
there's issues that we can explore on the way there.
在我们前往那里的途中，有一些问题我们可以探讨。
For example, Tao was working on remotely controlled vehicles,
例如，陶正在研究遥控车辆，
which, could be thought as an inter in STEM to autonomous vehicles.
它可以被认为是STEM领域对自动驾驶车辆的一种介入。
But it could also be thought, as a model, by itself.
但它也可以被认为是一个独立的模型。
Looking at the future of smart vehicles.
展望智能汽车的未来。
So, with that, hopefully brief introduction, I will let our panelists
因此，在这简短的介绍之后，我将让我们的小组成员
give us a brief introduction of themselves and talk about these
因此，在这简短的介绍之后，我将让我们的小组成员给我们做一个简短的自我介绍，并谈论一下他们所关注的行业和组织的问题。
the issues that their industry and organizations are concerned about.
他们所关注的行业和组织的问题。
And then we will move on to discussion the sequence will be
然后我们将继续讨论，顺序将是
I will have Mike Westra from Ford first, followed by Ted Guild.
接下来我们首先会听取福特公司的Mike Westra发言，紧接着是Ted Guild。
And then finally, Tao from NIST.
接下来最后我们将听取来自NIST的Tao的发言。
So Mike, if you're ready please go ahead and
接下来，Mike，如果你准备好了，请开始吧。
unmute and give us your perspective.
取消静音并给我们分享你的观点。
>> Okay. Great, thank you, can you hear me?
>> 好的。太好了，谢谢你，你能听见我说话吗？
>> Yeah.
是的。
>> [COUGH] You can.
>> [咳嗽] 你可以。
I'm Mike Westra.
我是迈克·韦斯特拉。
I'm the manager of connected product cyber security at Ford Motor Company
我是福特汽车公司联网产品网络安全的经理。
and, to just want to thank everybody on the panel for being here today.
同时，我想感谢今天在座的各位嘉宾。
And so Christos asked to kind of highlight really quickly in just a minute or two,
同时，Christos提出希望能在一两分钟内迅速强调一下，
some of the challenges that automakers are facing around data at the moment.
一些汽车制造商目前在数据方面面临的挑战。
And so he highlighted especially
他特别强调了
the data that's being collected into the back end and
正在收集到后端的数据并且
it's kind of a confluence of cyber security and
它是网络安全与~!@#$%^&*()的一种汇合。
government policy in some ways ironically at the at the moment.
政府政策在某些方面当前具有讽刺意味。
So Europe.
所以，欧洲。
Is kinda working through a lot of the challenges right now, and
正处于解决许多挑战的过程中，并且
there's a couple of models that they've explored from.
他们已经探索了几种模型。
So their end goal is to provide sort of an open ecosystem,
所以他们的最终目标是提供一种开放的生态系统，
where the data can be shared among interested
在这个生态系统中，数据可以在有兴趣的各方之间共享，根据你所看的模型。
parties based on the model that you're looking at.
根据你所看的模型，这些数据可以在有兴趣的各方之间共享。
It's kinda along a continuum from the OEMs, or
它在一定程度上是沿着从原始设备制造商（OEM）这一端的连续体发展的，或者说是
kinda intended to be the stewards of the data with an extended sorta vehicle.
有点像是担任数据管理者的角色，而且是通过一种扩展型的车辆来实现的。
And this can be data from what had historically been
这些数据可能来源于历史上已经存在的
repair data all the way to geolocation data, driving behavior data.
修复数据一直到地理位置数据、驾驶行为数据。
So there's obviously a lot of PII concerns.
显然，这里存在很多个人身份信息（PII）的隐私问题。
So from one end to the extreme where the automakers are kinda the stewards,
所以从一个极端到另一个极端，汽车制造商在某种程度上成为了数据的管理者，
Europe seems to be advocating a neutral server sort of approach,
欧洲似乎在提倡一种中立服务器的方法，
where there's a neutral server that is kinda where the data gets collected.
欧洲似乎在提倡一种中立服务器的方法，这个服务器是数据收集发生的地方。
To requirements that the vehicle directly
满足要求，车辆直接
connect to any third party, theoretically,
连接到任何第三方，理论上，
the user has authorized to collect that data.
用户已授权收集那些数据。
To even some models that some of the aftermarket folks are advocating, where it
甚至一些售后服务人员所倡导的模型，它
mandates that their code actually execute inside of the safety vehicle environment,
强制要求他们的代码实际上在安全车辆环境内执行，
which automakers have a great deal of sort of heartburn over.
哪些汽车制造商对此感到非常头疼。
I'll focus mostly on kinda the side, and
我主要会关注一些侧面的问题。
some of the challenges really are data collection is not free.
一些挑战确实存在，因为数据收集并不是免费的。
And so a lot of the expectation,
因此很多人的期望是，
unfortunately from some of the aftermarket folks has been, well,
不幸的是，来自一些售后市场的人的态度是，嗯，
we'll make you guys collect the data and then and then give it to us.
我们会让你们收集数据，然后再把它交给我们。
And that's kinda unfortunately the approach that's occurring in some
这种做法不幸地在一些地方正在发生。
places in the US as the policy battle is being fought.
这场政策之战正在美国的一些地方进行着。
It's supposed extension of right to repair.
这是对维修权的潜在扩展。
The challenges is less, the normal IT kinds of
挑战较少，更多是常见的IT类型的
mechanisms to share the data with PKI and TLS,
数据共享机制与PKI和TLS相关联，
and some of that, is fairly well adapted.
有些部分已经相当适应了。
The bigger challenge is around a lot of the policy aspects.
这个更大的挑战在于许多政策方面。
And so there's a lot of hand waving on, well, who's gonna authorize that
因此，关于谁将会授权这一点，有很多含糊其辞的讨论。
customers and entities are really truly who they say they are?
客户和实体确实是他们所声称的那个人吗？
And that's really the cracks of the problem.
这确实是问题的关键所在。
It's less the technical aspects,
这更少是技术层面的问题，
and it's really boils down to much more of a policy kinda concern.
这实际上更多地归结为一种政策层面的关注。
Where, historically, the OEM is kinda the steward of the data,
在历史上，OEM 通常是数据的管理者，
steward of the customer.
在历史上，OEM 通常是数据的管理者，负责客户的管理。Folks are trying to challenge that, and then there's not
Folks are trying to challenge that, and then there's not
人们试图挑战这一点，然后就没有了
sorta the corresponding understanding of, well, how do I know that this person
那么，我怎么知道这个人对应的理解是什么呢？
that is demanding data from a particular vehicle is in fact the customer?
那么，要求提供特定车辆数据的实际上是客户吗？
Or is truly a valid aftermarket,
或者真的是一个合法的售后市场，
entity that should actually have access to the data?
实体是否确实应该获得数据访问权限？
One of the things that we fortunately do see when we look at the data for
我们幸运地看到的一件事是，当我们查看数据时
right to repair data, we see a lot of data that comes in from
我们看到了很多来自修理权数据的信息，我们在查看数据时幸运地看到，在中国和东欧的地方，
places in China and Eastern Europe.
在中国和东欧的地方。
And the data isn't sort of as sensitive today, but
数据如今并不是特别敏感，但是
there's certainly a large concern just handing over sensitive PII data
确实存在很大的担忧，只是随意地交出敏感的个人身份信息(PII)。
to entities that haven't been properly sorta authenticated.
向尚未得到适当认证的实体交出数据。
And truly capturing customer consent, that they really want that data exchanged.
确实捕捉到客户的同意，他们确实希望交换那些数据。
And so a lot of those policy areas are really underdeveloped or
很多这样的政策领域实际上还不够成熟或者说是
not really robustly defined.
很多这样的政策领域实际上还不够成熟或者说是不够严密地定义。
As well as just the business aspects of, well, who's paying to collect that data?
以及谁来支付收集这些数据的费用这样的商业问题。
Because cellular data is not free nor necessarily cheap in mass.
因为蜂窝数据并不是免费的，而且在大量使用时也不一定便宜。
And so there's a lot of challenges that will need to get sorted out probably over
因此，可能在接下来的几年里，会有许多挑战需要解决，以明确这一切将如何运作。
the next couple of years as to how that how that's all going to work.
因此，在接下来的几年里，我们需要解决许多挑战，以明确这一切将如何运作。
And so it's less on the vehicle side, but
因此，它与车辆方面的关系不大，而是更多地关注于其他方面，
it's a lot more on how is the data gonna be managed.
因此，它与车辆方面的关系不大，而是更多地关注于其他方面，主要是数据将如何被管理。So that's what I've got to share.
So that's what I've got to share.
因此，这就是我要分享的内容。
So Chris, if you want to hand it off to the next person.
所以Chris，如果你想把它交给下一个人。
>> Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，Mike。
Thank you. Thank you for
谢谢你。谢谢你为
highlighting all these important issues with data.
强调所有这些重要问题，并用数据支持。
So Ted, we'll let you come in.
那么泰德，我们会让你进来。
And I'm sure you have a few things to say about data.
我相信你对数据肯定有一些看法。
So go ahead.
那就请继续。
>> Sure, my name is Ted Guild.
当然，我的名字是特德·吉尔德。
I'm a researcher at MIT where I've been the last 20 years.
我是麻省理工学院的一名研究员，过去20年我一直在那里工作。
A good chunk of that has been, well, all that's been working for the W3C.
其中很大一部分，嗯，全部都是为W3C工作的。
Good chunk, that is the head of IT organization where we also did,
很大一部分，那是IT组织的领导部分，我们也在那里工作过，
not just the infrastructure for the organization and defenses for
不仅仅是为组织提供基础设施和防御措施，还有我们自己，但也在研究一些新的网络安全原型。
ourselves, but working on sort of new web security sort of prototypes.
我们自己，但也在研究一些新的网络安全原型。
Try to sorta lead by example kinda thing.
试图以身作则，有那么一回事。
Currently, I am the lead of the WC automotive activity,
目前，我是WC汽车活动的负责人，
which I'll describe in brief.
我将简要描述一下。
I'm also the stock contact for the geospatial on the web activity.
我还是网络地理空间活动的股票联络人。
And I also do some secondary research on
我还进行一些次级研究。
connective vehicles and [INAUDIBLE].
联网车辆和[无法听清]。
So in brief, the [INAUDIBLE] vehicle ecosystem.
因此，简而言之，[无法听清]车辆生态系统。
It's also possible to run this on data that's already been off boarded and
它也可以运行在已经下线的数据上。
resides in the cloud.
它位于云端。
We're using a common data model.
我们正在使用一个通用的数据模型。
Every auto manufacturer currently does data differently,
每个汽车制造商目前处理数据的方式都不同，
which makes trying to normalize and use that more difficult.
这使得尝试标准化并使用这些数据变得更加困难。
And I'm enjoying a Mike Westra's photo problem in the background.
我在背景中欣赏着迈克·韦斯特拉的照片问题。
Better someone's messing with him real time.
最好是有人正在实时地捣乱他。
Always be careful of security conferences, even remote ones.
始终要小心安全会议，即便是远程的。
So come in data model, we're joined in collaboration Genivi.
所以加入了数据模型，我们正在与Genivi合作。
We're using web technologies because the various people that are.
我们正在使用网络技术，因为各种人都在使用。
OEMs, something they've watched it in the vehicle now established partnerships,
OEMs（原始设备制造商），他们已经在车辆中观察到这一点，并且现在已经建立了合作伙伴关系，
some they may be coerced to in time.
有些人可能会随着时间的推移而被迫这么做。
These guys are not the Automotive Engineers.
这些人不是汽车工程师。
But most of them should be familiar with web technologies since
但他们中的大多数应该熟悉网络技术，因为
that's the most dominant platform on the planet on the planet.
这是地球上最主导的平台。
We're bringing to the cloud.
我们正在将其迁移到云端。
We have an ontology that we build on top of this common data model, the SSO,
我们在这个通用数据模型之上构建了一个本体，即SSO，
which enables artificial intelligence machine learning, various analytics and
它使得人工智能机器学习、各种分析能够实现，
enables WC's web of things, which is an abstraction layer on top of IoT,
使得WC的物联网之网得以实现，这是建立在物联网之上的一个抽象层，
which is fragmented as badly if not worse than automotive.
它甚至比汽车行业更加碎片化。
Ask for help sorta abstract out normalize things and you can define a car as
求助于某种程度上的抽象化和标准化事物，你可以将一辆车定义为
a thing on the WC's web of things, decide what capabilities you want to expose.
在万维网联盟（W3C）的物联网中，决定你想要暴露哪些功能。
There's also sort of a whole laundry list of things that this sorta opens up.
这也在某种程度上揭开了一长串可能涉及的事项的序幕。
As far as these technologies, there's definitely a need for it and
就这些技术而言，它们无疑是有需求的，并且
via best practices, things that can help other manufacturers feel comfortable,
通过最佳实践，这些做法可以帮助其他制造商感到安心，
laying people in as far as this periodic reviews, what they're allowed to awkward,
通过定期审查，了解他们被允许的范围，尽管这可能会让人感到尴尬，
that sort of a resources making sure that in bandwidth is being paid for
确保带宽资源得到相应的支付。
in a reasonable and ideally non-discriminatory turns.
以合理且理想的非歧视性方式轮流进行。
Various things like that.
各种各样的事情。
We're also have a few things on the back burner as far as going forward.
我们也有一些事情暂时搁置，以便将来继续推进。
I try to stay on the technical solutions and
我尽量专注于技术解决方案和
avoid the political topics in the space.
避免在这个领域讨论政治话题。
But of course, I have my own views,
但当然了，我有我自己的看法，
I think that there is a possibility to have a medium and
我认为有可能存在一个中介和
safe environment between OEMs, these third parties are clamoring for data.
在OEMs之间的安全环境中，这些第三方正在争吵索要数据。
And I agree that is if OEMs are incurring costs and
如果OEMs在承担成本，并且
>> Very good.
>> 非常好。
Thank you, Ted.
谢谢你，Ted。
[COUGH] All right, so Tao, please go ahead,
好的，那么Tao，请开始吧。
introduce yourself and tell us a little bit about what you do.
介绍一下你自己，告诉我们一些关于你工作的事情。
>> Okay, hi everyone, this is Tao Zhang from NIST.
好的，大家好，我是来自NIST的张涛。
I joined NIST last year, just about a year ago.
我去年加入了NIST，大约就在一年前。
I manage the Emerging Network Technologies Group at NIST.
我在NIST管理新兴网络技术组。
So before joining NIST, I was in the private sector, doing research and
在加入NIST之前，我在私营部门从事研究和产品开发，以及企业战略。
product development, and corporate strategy.
产品开发和企业战略。
I was with Cisco Systems for about six weeks, I was the CTO chief scientist for
我在思科系统公司工作了大约六周，我是首席技术官兼首席科学家，负责
Cisco's smart connected vehicles business.
我在思科的智能互联汽车业务部门工作。
Helped actually build that business, and I was a chief scientist,
帮助实际构建了那个业务，我曾是首席科学家，
and director of research groups in Bellcore/Telcordia.
并且是Bellcore/Telcordia研究小组的负责人。
So which is part of the system over the data focus of
那么哪一部分是系统中关注数据的重点？
work has been vehicle to networking andwireless.
工作已经成为了网络和无线通信的载体。
So today, really a great pleasure to be here to share with everyone
今天真的很高兴能在这里和大家分享。
some thoughts as I'd like to mention maybe two areas.
我想提到两个方面的一些想法。
One of them, so we all know as Ted and Mike mentioned already,
他们两个人，正如泰德和迈克已经提到的，
data generated by the cars is an tremendous new issue.
汽车产生的数据是一个巨大的新问题。
And we all know there's a ton of data being generated on an hourly basis,
我们都知道，每小时都会产生大量的数据，
those are the data we need to train our machine learning models to do things,
这些数据是我们需要用来训练机器学习模型去做事情的。
to monitor the car, to control the car, and to protect a car.
监控汽车、控制汽车以及保护汽车。
So currently, what we do is that we send all this data to the cloud.
所以目前我们所做的是将所有这些数据发送到云端。
And we train machine learning models over there and
我们在那里训练机器学习模型，然后将模型发送回汽车中使用。
that was sent the models back to the cars to use.
将模型发送回汽车中使用。
And sending those data to the cloud is getting more and more invisible.
将这些数据发送到云端变得越来越不显眼。
So then the question is, did we explore other other capabilities?
那么问题就是，我们是否探索了其他的能力？
For example, agile learning.
例如，敏捷学习。
Can we have those cars to learn locally?
我们能否让那些汽车在本地学习？
But of course, the cars are limited in process and powers,
但当然，这些汽车在处理能力和功率上有限制，
they're limited in data, even though they have a lot,
它们的数据是有限的，即使它们拥有很多，
but they don't have to global view of it, everything.
但它们并没有对一切事物都有一个全局的视角。
And the question is what can those cars learn?
那么问题是，那些汽车能学到什么？
And how can they share the knowledge they learned from their local data
那么它们如何分享它们从本地数据中学到的知识呢？
with the cloud?
那么它们是如何与云端协作的呢？
So the cloud rather than collecting raw data from every cars,
因此，云端不是收集来自每辆车的原始数据，
can be collecting knowledge learned by the cars and transferred to the cloud.
可以收集汽车学到的知识并将其传输到云端。
And then they can leverage those to build better and more powerful models.
然后他们可以利用这些知识来构建更好、更强大的模型。
So the knowledge learn, for example, in terms of machine learning models,
所学到的知识，例如在机器学习模型方面，
parameters and so on, and it will be much,
参数等等，它会小很多，
much smaller than the size of the raw data.
比原始数据的大小要小得多。
And so
much smaller than the original data size. That's one of the areas I think maybe worth while looking into in the future.
that's one of the areas I think maybe worth while looking into in the future.
这是我认为将来值得研究的领域之一。
Another area is over the past several yeas, two, three years I will say,
另一个领域是在过去的几年里，我会说，两三年来，
and there is an increasing amount of effort in the industry and
以及行业内日益增加的努力在于
developing not just self driving cars but remote controlled cars.
开发的不仅仅是自动驾驶汽车，还有遥控汽车。
So remote driving are tiny operation.
所以远程驾驶是微小的操作。
So today for example, that effort has been focused mostly on use and
因此，例如今天，这种努力主要集中在使用上。
human remote drivers to help autonomous cars to handle tougher tricky
Therefore, for instance today, such efforts are primarily focused on the use of human remote drivers to assist autonomous cars in handling tougher, tricky cases that the cars themselves do not have enough intelligence to handle yet.
cases that the cars themselves do not have enough intelligence to handle yet.
这些情况是汽车本身还没有足够的智能来处理的。
And there happens to be quite a lot still.
而且那里恰好还有很多。
And they are already a lot of interesting issues over there,
而且那里已经有很多有趣的问题了，
trying to overcome.
研究人员正试图克服。
But for researchers,
但对于研究人员来说，
actually you can see bigger potentials along that direction.
实际上，沿着那个方向你可以看到更大的潜力。
So we don't have to stop at human teleoperators
所以我们不必停留在人类遥操作者这一步。
as the network's become better well as we move into 5G.
随着网络变得更好，以及我们进入5G时代。
As the AI capabilities become more advanced, you could envision that one day,
随着人工智能能力的不断进步，你可以想象有一天，
it could become possible that the technologies will allow us to
技术将使我们能够
even offload some of the driving intelligence away from the cars.
甚至将部分驾驶智能从汽车中卸载出去。
And to the edge systems to the cloud systems.
并将其扩展到边缘系统和云系统。
And so you'll see and as sort of an interesting
因此，你会看到这是一种有趣的
framework that allows you to distribute and
因此，你会看到这是一种有趣的框架，它允许你分布和驾驭沿着车辆与云端之间连续体的智能。
driving intelligence along that continuum between the vehicle and the cloud.
驾驭在车辆与云端之间连续体上的智能驾驶。
And so with the two extremes being who is the white straight away extreme being all
因此，两个极端分别是，一个极端完全是白色的直线。
the intelligence and being placed on the car that is what we have today.
所以我们今天拥有的是智能化并被安置在汽车上的技术。
And so the question then becomes, and will that be visible,
所以接下来的问题就是，这将会是可见的吗？
how would that be visible, what it depends on?
那将如何可见，它取决于什么？
And what would you be challenges for example,
那么，例如你会遇到什么挑战呢？
people will immediately point out, hey, what about the network?
人们会立刻指出，嘿，网络怎么样了？
What happens if the natural delays get bad and so on?
如果自然延迟变得很糟糕会怎么样呢？
So there are challenges.
所以存在着挑战。
And so that is another area that I think maybe it was loud looking into.
所以我认为那是另一个可能值得深入研究的领域。
So I'll stop there, thank you >> Thank you, Tao, thank you very much.
所以我就说到这里，谢谢 >> 谢谢你，陶，非常感谢。
So those were the presentations from our presenters and
所以这些就是我们演讲者的报告内容。
I do encourage the audience to ask questions as as they come along.
我鼓励观众随时提出问题。
I wanted to start by sort of addressing what the Tao said and ask Mike.
我想首先解读一下道的说法并询问迈克。
So Mike, I'll put on a very compelling view for
所以迈克，我将展示一个非常引人注目的观点来讨论
what the future of smart and connected vehicles might look like.
智能和互联车辆的未来可能是什么样子。
Is this something that the automakers are looking at?
这是汽车制造商正在考虑的事情吗？
Can you tell us a little bit about how Ford and in general, the automakers,
您能否谈谈福特乃至一般汽车制造商是如何考虑的？
are looking at the future of autonomous vehicles?
我们是否在展望自动驾驶汽车的未来？
Is this still l four, l five, or are we looking at interim solutions or
我们是在考虑四级、五级自动驾驶，还是在寻找过渡性的解决方案？
ten alternatives?
十种替代方案？
>> I think you'll see this is the state of the art advanced for
>> 我认为你会看到这是最先进的状态
long to two kind of pipelines.
长达两种类型的管道。
One's sort of what really is kind of advanced and
一种是真正意义上相当先进的
those will start to bleed into like level two.
这些将开始渗透进入类似于二级的层面。
And they'll have more and more connectivity, and
它们将拥有越来越多的连通性，
they'll allow more to be done kind of with the with the operator,
它们将允许操作者可以做更多的事情，
sort of ultimately in control.
最终某种程度上处于控制之中。
And you'll start to see more sort of vision systems, radar, and
你将开始看到更多的视觉系统、雷达等，
more sensors sort of supporting that beyond even what Tesla is doing today.
你将开始看到更多的传感器开始支持这一点，甚至超出了特斯拉今天所做的。
And then the autonomous vehicles will kind of work from the top down,
然后自动驾驶汽车将会从上至下开始工作，
where pretty much the state of the art now is sort of
我们现在基本上处于技术的前沿，可以说是
safety operator driven level 4 autonomous vehicles.
安全操作员驾驶的四级自动驾驶汽车。
And they have probably a couple of 100,000$ in sensors
而且他们的传感器可能价值几十万美元。
that will all become much cheaper over time.
随着时间的推移，这些都将变得便宜得多。
I think a lot of people see those as being more fleet centric,
我认为很多人将这些视为更多地以车队为中心，
at least for the short and medium term.
至少在短期和中期内。
You read the press where a lot of that investment is, is being driven
您阅读了新闻报道，很多投资正是由此推动的。
by the likes of Google and Uber, along with the traditional automakers.
由谷歌和优步等公司以及传统汽车制造商所推动。
And so you'll see a lot of that kind of driven lower and lower.
因此，你会看到很多这种情况被不断压低。
But the reality is a lot of that where the intent there is to get rid of
但实际情况是，很多时候这样做的意图是为了摆脱
the steering wheel and provide sort of service.
摆脱方向盘并提供某种服务。
That requires a whole different level of safety and
那需要一个完全不同层次的安全性和
compute and sensors, sort of completely different than Edaf.
计算和传感器，这与Edaf完全不同。
Where Edaf can kind of just say, you know what it's raining,
Edaf能够直接告诉你，你知道的，它在下雨，
I don't know how to deal with this current situation,
我不知道如何处理当前的情况，
I'm gonna make the operator sort of deal with it.
我会让操作员来处理这件事。
level 4 has to be fully autonomous within a geo fenced area and
四级自动驾驶必须在地理围栏区域内完全自主。
level 5 is in theory anywhere in the country.
五级自动驾驶理论上可以在国内任何地方行驶。
It could fully operate autonomously and
它可以完全自主地运行并且
I think even the most aggressive sort of futurists say level 5
我认为即使是最激进的未来主义者也会说5级自动驾驶还有很长的路要走，其中4级自动驾驶是大家都在努力达到的目标。
is quite a ways out where level 4 is where everybody's trying to shoot
是相当遥远的目标，而4级自动驾驶则是大家都在努力追求的。
first a sweet spot in terms of how much is going to be onboard versus off board.
首先要找到一个甜蜜点，确定有多少是要安装在车上的，而有多少是要放在车外的。
I think, I don't think we're necessarily unique.
我认为，我并不认为我们有什么特别之处。
In the sort of approach, I think from a safety standpoint, and
在这种方法中，我认为从安全的角度来看，
this is even less cybersecurity, the final decisions as to sort of braking, steering,
在这种方法中，我认为从安全的角度来看，最终决定诸如制动、转向这类操作，
all of the safety operations are done sort of locally on the edge.
所有的安全操作都是在本地边缘进行的。
And where the cloud comes in, is it will help with the learning,
云端的作用在于它将有助于学习过程，
the process that the tons of processing that's needed for maps and
处理大量地图所需的过程是
for helping around sort of exception.
帮助处理某种例外情况。
So the autonomous vehicle
所以自动驾驶汽车
encounters something it's not,it's sort of anticipating, such as a sort
遇到了它没有预料到的东西，比如一种以前不知道的建筑区域。
of construction zone that wasn't previously known.
它可能会因为遇到了一种以前不知道的建筑区域而停下来警觉。
It may stop alert, the back end and
它可能会停下来警觉，后端以及~!@#$%^&*()
then have to have the back end with some operators support.
然后必须有后端得到一些操作员的支持。
Add that to the to the mapping on the fly.
将其即时添加到映射中。
That in routing types of sort of macro routing types of things would
将其即时添加到映射中，可能正在后端发生的局部决策，这在路由类型中属于某种宏观路由类型的事务。
could be happening on the back end the local decision.
可能正在后端发生的局部决策。
In terms of this object will almost certainly be done on the edge
在这个对象上的处理几乎肯定会在边缘完成。
just because of safety concerns.
仅仅是因为安全考虑。
>> Great.
很好。
Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，迈克。
Before I let you off the hook, Mike I, wanted to, so well, let me do this first.
在我放你走之前，迈克，我想，那么，让我先做这个。
First of all, let me see if the other two panelists have any.
首先，让我看看其他两位小组成员是否有任何意见。
Follow one on what Mike said though Tao or Ted?
跟随迈克所说的，不过是陶还是泰德呢？
>> A little bit so I agree with Mike that.
我在某种程度上同意迈克的看法。
As far as decisions things need to be done on the edge on the vehicle itself
在决策方面，需要在车辆本身的边缘进行操作。
directly.
直接地。
You don't have the time for the turnarounds at the send something off and
你没有时间去等待发送东西并且直接地。希望能有一个决定。
hope for a decision.
希望能有一个决定。
But to tell us point sort of earlier insert combining with Mike's.
但要告诉我们的要点是，稍早一点插入，结合迈克的意见。
I do want that information to be off boarded as well and sort of feed.
我也希望那些信息能够被顺利转移并得到传播。
Right now we're seeing quite
当前我们正目睹着相当多的
a bit of competition sort of a race towards autonomous vehicles and
我们正在见证一种竞争，有点像是向着自动驾驶汽车发展的竞赛。
automated pastures are traditionally both collaborative and competitive.
自动化牧场传统上既具有合作性也具有竞争性。
Limit how and where they collaborate.
限制他们合作的方式和范围。
I think we'll see some partnerships start emerge, more partnerships start emerged
我认为我们将会看到一些合作伙伴关系开始出现，更多的合作伙伴关系将会浮现。
around autonomous vehicles that some of them feel there may be falling behind.
我认为他们中的一些人感觉可能会落后，所以我们将会看到围绕自动驾驶汽车的一些合作伙伴关系开始出现。
And I see them start to get into federated learning and
我看到他们开始涉足联合学习领域，
be able to use the data available on both are multiple fleets
能够利用多个车队上可用的数据
from different auto manufacturers and be able to feed those in and learn from them.
能够从不同汽车制造商那里获取数据，并能够整合这些数据并从中学习。
Because the variation of sensors and
由于传感器的变化以及
these mechanics of the vehicles together will help to create a better understanding
这些车辆的机械原理结合起来将有助于更好地理解
of the physical world that these objects are moving.
这些物体移动所在的物理世界。
I think I'll just, he wants to say something as well.
我认为我会，他也想说点什么。
Go ahead. Sorry.
继续吧。对不起。
>> No, I'm good.
>> 不，我很好。
No, no, I was done.
不，不，我已经完成了。
Off to you, sir.
给您，先生。
[BLANK_AUDO] >> Yeah,
~!@#$%^&*()
so I view this collective learning between for
所以我认为这是一种集体学习过程
example and a vehicle and in the cloud.
因此，作为下一步，我们在车辆上对数据进行了大量的预处理，并且在云端。
Sort of as the next step, we do a lot of pre processing of data on the vehicle,
所以，作为下一步，我们在车辆上对数据进行了大量的预处理，
right?
对吧？
We try to filter out things we think, are not useful for certain applications.
我们尝试过滤掉我们认为对某些应用程序不有用的东西。
And we don't send everything generated by the vehicle to the cloud or
我们并不会把车辆生成的所有数据发送到云端或者
IT, but this sort of collective collaborative learning.
但这种集体协作学习。
Between those two entities one and the cloud and
在这两个实体之间，一个是云端，
a car sort of represent a next step, right now, rather than sort of a selectively
一辆车在某种程度上代表了下一个阶段，目前，与其说是选择性地
transform, transporting data back and forth, we actually move to one step up.
在转换和传输数据的过程中，我们实际上是向前迈进了一步。
We actually build knowledge and we started to select which knowledge will learn to
我们实际上在构建知识，并开始选择将要学习哪些知识。
share with other people and how do you share and sharing knowledge actually.
与其他人分享以及如何分享，实际上分享知识也是如此。
Turns out to be and the more complicated matter.
事实证明，这是一件更为复杂的事情。
And then sharing all that has that opens up a lot of interesting research
然后分享所有这些内容，这为许多有趣的研究打开了大门。
questions for the researchers on this call.
此问题是针对在此通话中的研究人员的。
So that's where I think it's important and it and
所以我认为这就是它的重要之处。
also this distributed sort of learning.
这种分布式的学习方式。
And goes beyond what the traditional does do.
并且超越了传统所做的。
As you know today, distributed learning has been going on for quite some time.
您知道的，分布式学习已经进行了相当长的一段时间。
But they tend to focus on distributed learning in a cloud setup.
但他们倾向于专注于云环境中的分布式学习。
So which is very,
所以这与协作式边缘学习和云学习有很大的不同。
very different from the collaborative edge learning and cloud learning.
因此，这与协作式边缘学习和云学习有很大的不同。
In the cloud, for example,
在云端，例如，
you will have data that's accessible by all the distributee knows.
你将拥有所有分发者都能访问的数据。
Right.
好的。
And it's the same day and they did it.
而且是同一天，他们做到了。
Yeah. The computers and
是的。电脑和~!@#$%^&*()
the cloud nodes are not that limited by processing power.
云节点在处理能力上并不那么受限。
They're much secure and much more secure than for example, the edge nodes.
它们比如边缘节点要安全得多。
And so you can have different ways to handle robustness and
因此，你可以有不同的方法来处理健壮性和
trustworthiness of the models.
模型的可信赖性。
And when you have sort of cars helping you learn, and all of those
当你有些许汽车在帮助你学习，以及所有这些
fundamental assumptions change and most of them don't hold true anymore.
基本假设发生了变化，而且它们中的大多数不再成立。
That impacts the way you develop methods and methods for learning so
这影响了你制定学习方法和方法的方式，所以
and in the future, not even very far future.
这将影响你未来，甚至不是很遥远的未来，制定学习方法和方法的方式。所以，那些在边缘学习的人可能会变得必不可少。
So, those learning at edge may become a necessity just
因此，那些在边缘学习的人可能会变得必不可少。
because the sheer amount of data you're generating and
因为你生成的数据量巨大且
you can or you don't want to send them all into the cloud so
因为你不想把它们全部发送到云端，所以
they just sort of want to add to that.
他们只是想要进一步补充那个。
>> Very good.
>> 非常好。
Thank you Tao.
谢谢陶。
Another question for all three of you right now.
再问你们三个人一个问题。
So we're seeing sort of a convergence between internet technologies and
所以我们正在见证互联网技术与
automotive communication systems and part of it has been facilitated by the move.
所以我们正在见证互联网技术与汽车通信系统的结合，而这一进程部分得益于这一转变。或者是汽车以太网的明显采用。
Or the apparent adoption of automotive Ethernet
或者是汽车以太网的明显采用。
by the automotive industry, which, with automotive Ethernet,
已经被汽车行业所采用，特别是随着汽车以太网的明显采用，
we're now looking at much higher speeds, much bigger packets.
我们现在正在考虑更高的速度，更大的数据包。
An environment where the internet folks now feel
互联网用户现在感觉到的一种环境
more comfortable in terms of bringing in technologies that they've developed for
更加舒适地引入他们开发的技术，以适应
the internet such as security encryption, authentication and so forth.
互联网的安全加密、认证等方面。
Our audience is mostly internet researchers.
我们的受众主要是互联网研究人员。
So what would you like to see from internet researchers
那么，您希望从互联网研究人员那里看到什么？
in terms of contributing or collaborating with the automotive sector?
在汽车行业的贡献或合作方面？
Are there other good opportunities?
还有其他好的机会吗？
Are there obvious things that the automotive sector
汽车行业有哪些明显的事情？
can collaborate with internet researchers?
可以与互联网研究人员合作吗？
>> Sure, I'll take the first swing at it.
当然，我会先来尝试一下。
I think yeah, I mean,
我认为是的，我的意思是，
it's very true that sort of Ethernet is becoming kind of a, I think well.
它非常真实，以太网正在变得有点像，我认为很好。
V the default high speed link and things like flex Ray and
大多数可能会很快被它所取代。
that some automakers had used for high speed links.
一些汽车制造商用于高速链接的技术。
That doesn't mean that is necessarily going away anytime soon for real time and
这并不意味着它会很快在实时中消失。
other uses I had, our sort
我还有其他用途，我们的那种方式。
of lead network expert kinda described it this way.
首席网络专家这样描述过。
Unlike a somebody who's setting up sort of an IT network on an enterprise,
与那些在企业中建立某种IT网络的人不同，
where they have to, basically make sure that the network is set up.
他们必须确保网络得到正确设置。
You've got dozens, in hundreds, or thousands of clients.
你可能有几十个、几百个甚至几千个客户。
It's kind of the opposite in a vehicle.
在车辆中情况恰恰相反。
You need determinism, reliability,
你需要确定性、可靠性，
and you're building the same relatively small network with maybe.
你正在构建一个相对较小的网络，可能会有。
Anywhere from four to a couple of dozen nodes on it, but
它上面可能有四到几十个节点，但是
you're building that same network a million different times.
你正在以一百万种不同的方式构建相同的网络。
And it's in your basically replicating it nearly identically,
你基本上是在近乎完全相同地复制它，
sort of a million times as you're building vehicles, and
你在制造车辆的过程中，基本上是在近乎完全相同地复制它，大约一百万次，而且
you need to make sure that that network behaves reliably and
你需要确保那个网络可靠地运行，并且
sort of operates consistently.
需要保证它能够稳定运行。
And then just from a sort of a technology standpoint,
从技术角度来看，
I think on the wire, you're gonna see a number of similarities.
我认为在传输层，你会发现很多相似之处。
So you'll still have TCP/IP and UDP.
所以你仍然会使用TCP/IP和UDP。
On the wire, the physical wiring will be different just because of some of the,
在传输介质上，物理布线会有所不同，这是因为一些...
>> [COUGH]
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Unique physical properties in
独特的物理特性在
the vehicle, and some of the cost constraints and
车辆以及一些成本限制和
you may see a few additional things on the network,
您可能会在网络上看到一些额外的东西，
such as sort of time synchronization for media and some other types of things.
例如某种时间同步媒体和其他一些类型的东西。
And you may see statically defined networks that go back
和你可能会看到静态定义的网络，它们可以追溯到
to making sure that everything is consistent and whatnot.
确保一切都是一致的等等。
But at the same time, from a security standpoint.
但同时，从安全的角度来看。
There's a lot of excitement, hey, can I use VLANs?
有很多兴奋，我可以使用VLANs吗？
Can I start to do things that add various sort of switching and
我可以开始做添加各种交换功能的事情吗？
firewall layers to just sort of isolate and shape traffic for
防火墙层用来隔离和塑造流量，以便
that things are isolated and segregated appropriately to keep domains separate.
事物被适当地隔离和分开，以保持领域的独立性。
So, I think it's similar.
所以，我认为它们是相似的。
You'll see a lot of echoes and rhymes.
你会看到许多呼应和韵律。
But there'll be slight oddities and
但会有些轻微的怪异和
differences in a real time system like that, if that makes sense.
在这样的实时系统中会有一些差异，如果这话说得通的话。
>> Yeah, great. Thank you, Mike.
是的，很好。谢谢你，迈克。
Tao, how do you feel about
是的，很好。谢谢你，迈克。这种互联网与汽车环境的融合。
this merging of internet with the automotive environment.
这种互联网与汽车环境的融合。
One of the questions that we've been asking
我们一直在问的一个问题
is the clearly automotive in the automotive space.
是在汽车领域中明显的汽车相关内容。
There's a really important security of indication, encryption requirements.
这是一个非常重要的安全指标，加密要求。
And now the automotive industry is looking at internet technologies.
现在汽车行业正在关注互联网技术。
is do you think that would be sufficient?
你认为那样足够吗？
Or do we need to work on different approaches that suit
我们是否需要采取不同的方法来适应
the automotive space better?
我们是否需要采取不同的方法来适应汽车领域更好？>> Yeah, I think that's a very, very important question.
>> Yeah, I think that's a very, very important question.
是的，我认为这是一个非常非常重要的问题。
[COUGH] So I think what we do need a lot of help
（咳嗽）所以我认为我们确实需要很多帮助
from the internet community in this area insecurity and trustworthiness.
从互联网社区在这一领域的不安全感和可信度。
But I think automotive do bring in a very unique
但我认为汽车确实带来了一种非常独特的
set of challenges that even today's, state of the art security
一套挑战，即便是今天的最先进安全技术也难以应对。
paradigm that we use for the internet [COUGH] may not be adequate enough.
我们用于互联网的范例可能还不够充分。
So [COUGH] several examples and
因此，好几个例子和
incidence response.
事件响应。
And think about sort of the hallway respond to incidences and
并考虑一下走廊如何对事件做出响应。
to our computers.
给我们的电脑。
You got a virus on the computer.
你的电脑中了病毒。
So what do you do, right?
那你会怎么做呢，对吧？
You typically send it to some expert and the expert shutting down and
你通常会把它送给某个专家，然后专家会关闭设备，
trying to diagnose them to replace software, hardware, whenever necessary and
尝试诊断它们以便在必要时替换软件、硬件，以及
reboot it, and you just simply cannot do that to a car.
重新启动它，你就是不能对一辆车这么做。
And so [COUGH] then the question is what do you do?
那么问题就是你该怎么办？
And I don't think we have a good answer yet.
我认为我们还没有一个好的答案。
So that is and that is an area I think people can build upon
所以那是一个我认为人们可以进一步发展的领域。
what we have and to really sort of come up with solutions for automotive.
我们所拥有的，以及真正提出汽车解决方案的努力。
I'll give you another example that actually there are a quite I have quite
我会再给你一个例子，实际上有很多，我有很多
a long list of this.
这里面有一长串这样的例子。
Another example of sort of the uniqueness abroad to bide automotives,
另一个例子是，国外独有的一种汽车，它们具有某种独特性。
well, no sort of automotives are very sensitive to cost, and the processing
嗯，没有哪种汽车对成本非常敏感，而且加工过程...
powers as a result on the automotive side are usually relatively more restricted.
因此，在汽车方面的权力通常相对更受限制。
And then for example our computers and cellphones and however at
因此，例如我们的电脑和手机等，然而在……
the same time our car needs to run on the road for an average of 14 years.
同样，我们的汽车平均需要在道路上行驶14年。
So that's a long lifespan.
所以那是一个很长的寿命。
And security has this thing about, it goes out of date very quickly so
安全性方面有一个特点，那就是它很快就会过时，所以
you need to catch up this security software all the time.
你需要一直更新这个安全软件。
Right, you need to update it to counter the more sort of advanced threats.
对，你需要更新它来对抗那些更高级的威胁。
And over that long span of lifespan,
而在那么长的生命周期里，
there is real sort of a high probabilities that sometime down the road.
在未来的某个时刻，真的有很高的可能性。
Your new security software may not be such that your hardware on the corner may be
在将来的某个时刻，你的新安全软件可能会变得无法在你现有的硬件上运行，因为它可能过于陈旧，无法支持你的安全软件更新。
too outdated to support your security software updates.
过于陈旧，无法支持你的安全软件更新。
And then what do you do?
那么你接下来要做什么呢？
Right in theory, you could make the hardware sort of plug and play.
理论上来说，你确实可以让硬件支持即插即用。
You could swap them but nobody wants to do that, right.
你可以交换它们，但没人想这么做，对吧。
That's a hustle.
这是一种套路。
That's a reputation hedge.
这是一种声誉保护措施。
That creates inconvenience, that creates fear in the driver's minds,
这造成了不便，也在司机心中植入了恐惧，
like what's going on with my sort of device.
这让我感到困惑，我的设备到底发生了什么事。
And so unless in a fleet environment where sort
这样一来，除非是在一个由专家团队管理更新的公司车队环境中，
of a company have an army of experts handling their updates, and
在这种情况下，一个公司拥有一个由专家组成的团队来处理他们的更新，
even individual carmakers may sort of this may be difficult, sort of another area for
即使是各个汽车制造商可能在某种程度上这可能是困难的，另一个领域可能也是如此。
example, AI is becoming more and more embedded into.
例如，人工智能正变得越来越嵌入其中。
Cars especially self driving cars, and AI come with a slew of unique
汽车，尤其是自动驾驶汽车，以及人工智能伴随着一系列独特的
security issues, especially when applied to automotive and
安全问题，特别是当应用于汽车和
people started to discover many of those.
人们开始发现了许多这样的问题。
And but overall, I think our understanding of that is still very, very weak.
但总的来说，我认为我们对此的理解仍然非常非常薄弱。
And I think sort of a better understanding of how those AI based modules used
而我认为对于这些基于人工智能的模块如何使用有了更好的理解。
in the car will sort of impose even more security vulnerabilities to cars.
在汽车中将会在一定程度上增加更多的安全漏洞。
I think will be a must.
我认为这将是必须的。
So, yeah, those are just some a few examples.
所以，是的，这些只是一些例子。
>> Thank you Tao.
>> 谢谢陶。
I have relevant question from the audience.
我有一个来自观众的相关问题。
He is asking about data availability for research in machine learning.
他在询问关于机器学习研究中数据的可用性。
It is obviously expensive, and also challenging to collect data
收集数据显然是昂贵的，同时也具有挑战性。
from multiple vehicles to do distributed machine learning.
从多个车辆中进行分布式机器学习。
Any thoughts on how we can help the researchers either
我们能如何帮助研究人员或者获得高质量的数据，或许还能降低此类研究的成本？
get access to high quality data or perhaps keep the cost down of such research?
获取高质量数据或者或许还能降低此类研究的成本？
>> It's possible to do, is easier to do a present with aftermarket devices.
有可能做到，用售后设备做礼物会更容易。
As the vehicle provide their own network connection, get reverse engineering canvas
由于车辆提供了自己的网络连接，获取逆向工程画布。
that was mentioned in order to be able to sort of leverage to make use of that data,
这是为了能够利用那些数据而提到的。
but there's enough out there for
但那儿已经有足够多的资源可以利用了。
number of vehicles where you can do that, that would be my suggestion.
你可以这么做的车辆数量，这将是我的建议。
Trying to get Yen's to.
努力尝试去做到Yen的。
And their legal departments to part with data for
以及他们的法律部门分享数据以便于
researchers given the sensitivity of it, maybe more of a challenge, but
研究人员鉴于其敏感性，可能会面临更多的挑战，但是
by committee maybe respond to that better than I.
可能委员会比我更能更好地回应这一点。
>> Well, yeah.
嗯，是的。
And as soon as it's somehow, I mean,
而且一旦它不知怎么的，我是说，
that's, I think Venice folks know this quite well, as soon as you.
那是，我认为威尼斯人非常清楚，一旦你……
Are taking data from real customers in the field.
正在从实地的真实客户那里获取数据。
There's always that chance that you can D anonymize it if you're clever and
总有可能，如果你足够聪明，你可以将数据去匿名化。
then you're gonna do sort of legal and privacy sort of landmines.
那么你将会遇到一些法律和隐私方面的雷区。
One thing I would highlight, I don't just use University of Michigan as an example.
我想强调的一点是，我举的例子不仅仅是密歇根大学。
With M city and they're not the only ones, I think Virginia Tech and
与M城一样，他们并不是唯一的，我认为弗吉尼亚理工学院也是如此，还有一些其他学校也做了这个。
some others have done this.
有些其他学校也做了这个。
They've actually done research projects in the US case around like V2X,
他们实际上在美国的案例中围绕V2X做了研究项目，
where the research project itself is just to get the beginning of
他们的研究项目本身只是为了开始获得
a good based data set that they can use to build additional
一个良好的基础数据集，他们可以利用它来构建更多的
use for additional research, sort of after the fact.
用于后续的额外研究。
And so I have seen some academics, where they've sort of funded and
我看到一些学者，他们为此提供了资金并且
done actual projects to just get, get that data and
完成了实际项目来获取，获取那些数据并且
what's nice in that is they'll often pick a cart handful of mix and
他们经常会挑选一小车的混合物，这点很好，因为它可以帮助他们在一定程度上规范化那些数据。
models so that they can normalize that data a little bit as well.
他们这样做，也是为了能在一定程度上规范化那些数据。
And that's what you'll often find if you just pick a Ford or gym, or Toyota.
而如果你随便挑选一辆福特或吉姆，或是丰田车，你通常会发现的情况就是这样。
The data is gonna be similar but a lot if its going to be.
数据将会相似，但很多都会是这样。
Sort of a bit wonky to the specific sensors or
数据将会有所不同，特定于各个传感器或
how the network is put together.
网络是如何组建的。
And so that normalization is always a tricky thing to accomplish.
因此，实现标准化始终是一件棘手的事情。
>> Right, thanks Mike.
对，谢谢，迈克。
So another question I have to, I'm sorry.
所以我还有另一个问题，对不起。
Did you have a, did you want to respond to them?
你想回应他们吗？
>> No, I think we should probably go to the next one since there's a low on
不，我认为我们可能应该去下一个地方，因为那里人很少。
time and probably more.
时间，可能还有更多。
>> Great because the next one, the next question Ted is for you and Mike,
>> 很好，因为下一个问题，Ted，是为你和Mike准备的。
in some sense.
在某种意义上。
So one, so the question I have is,
所以我的问题是，
so both you and Mike have talked about data coming out of cars.
所以你和Mike都谈到了汽车输出的数据。
And Ted, you're a supporter of open data standards.
而且Ted，你是开放数据标准的支持者。
And making all these valuable data available to researchers,
并且让研究人员能够获取这些宝贵的数据，
to users, to anybody who needs the data.
向用户，向任何需要数据的人。
And Mike has pointed out to the cost of collecting the data.
迈克已经指出了收集数据的成本。
And sometimes the fact that, those who want the data seem to
有时候事实是，那些想要数据的人似乎忽略了收集数据的成本。
ignore that there's a cost associated with collecting the data.
忽略了收集数据相关的成本。
For example, the aftermarket, the old ways claimed the right to repair and they say,
例如，售后市场，传统方式主张维修权，他们说，
well, you need to give us all the data from the car because that's our job,
嗯，你需要提供车辆的所有数据，因为那是我们的工作，
we need the data to do the tuning and so forth.
我们需要这些数据来进行调校等工作。
So, our open data standards, a good idea and how do we implement them?
那么，我们的开放数据标准是一个好主意，我们应该如何实施它们呢？
How do we go about creating these standards?
我们应该如何制定这些标准呢？
So we don't disadvantage or
所以我们不要使某人处于不利地位或者
make it unfair for somebody, for
所以我们不要使某人处于不利地位或者不公平，为了让所有玩家能在这个空间中游戏。
all the players to play in this space.
让所有玩家能在这个空间中游戏。
So Ted I know you're doing a lot of work and you're applicating open standards,
所以泰德，我知道你在做很多工作，你正在应用开放标准，
I wanted to give you opportunity a little more about
我想给你更多的机会去了解一下~!@#$%^&*()
what your thoughts are in that space.
你在那个领域的想法是什么。
>> I am an advocate of open standards allow for more interoperability allow for
>> 我是开放标准的倡导者，这些标准允许更多的互操作性，允许
easier dissemination of data, as Mike was alluding to, it's not just the different
更容易传播数据，正如迈克所暗示的，这不仅仅是不同的
signals but it's also the variations what's needs some meditated.
信号，但也有变化，这需要一些深思熟虑。
The company said what's the degree of error with the given sensor.
公司询问所提供的传感器的误差程度是多少。
What was the sampling method it was collected on.
它是采用什么样的取样方法收集的。
And so
它是采用什么样的取样方法收集的。像很多OEM厂商那样，他们采用了一些固定时间间隔和……
like a lot of them a number of OEMs are doing some fixed time intervals and
像许多OEM厂商那样，他们采用了一些固定时间间隔和……
clicking 100 or whatever sensor data points and that's great and useful.
点击100个或其他任何传感器数据点，这很棒也很有用。
We answered a lot of questions, but it may not be able to answer a researcher's
我们回答了很多问题，但可能无法回答研究人员的
question which may be very specific.
问题可能非常具体。
And that's why we need sort of when we have something
我们需要这样做的原因是当我们有某事时候
that people are comfortable for safety and security reasons, allowing something to
为了安全和安保原因，让人们感到舒适，允许某些事情进行，
run the vehicle, they should be permitted to do their own data sampling.
为了安全和安保原因，让人们感到舒适，允许某些事情进行，运行车辆时，他们应该被允许进行自己的数据采样。他们应该承担成本并获得合理的利润。
They should be covering the cost plus a reasonable profit margin for
他们应该承担成本加上合理的利润空间。
the auto manufacturers to do that, because there's fixed cost and
他们应该承担成本加上合理的利润空间，因为存在固定成本和……我们进行投资资本投资。
we make the investment capital investment
我们进行投资资本投资。
on the computer resources from the vehicle and the ongoing costs of bandwidth.
关于车辆的计算机资源以及带宽的持续成本。
Those are real.
这些是真的。
And they need to be smart about not just what data points they collect,
他们需要聪明地选择不仅仅是他们收集哪些数据点，
but how they do that collection.
但他们如何进行那些数据的收集。
As I said, a lot of you are doing fixed intervals, and
正如我所说，你们中的许多人都在进行固定间隔的操作，而且
that's flawed, or it misses a lot.
这是有缺陷的，或者它错过了很多。
A lot can happen within those group that were doing with
在这些团体中可以发生很多事情。
one service provider every 23 seconds.
每23秒就有一家服务提供商。
That's why because you miss a lot in 23 seconds.
这就是为什么你在23秒内会错过很多东西。
There's a dispute future curve algorithm which
有一个未来曲线算法的争议，它
helps sort of measure like the peaks and valleys and
有助于某种程度上测量峰值和谷值
find pertinent data that will most likely been more useful once off boarded.
找到相关数据，这些数据一旦离开主体，很可能会更有用。
You need to be able to have new logic, they can also respond to events and
你需要能够拥有新逻辑，他们也能够对事件做出响应。
under certain situations, like a whole another set of data points.
在某些情况下，就像是一整套全新的数据点。
So there's, you.
所以那里有你。
There's absolutely no way that automated faster can collect data that will solve
绝对不可能有自动化更快的方式来收集数据以解决这个问题。
everyone's question.
每个人的问题。
Regulators, insurance carriers, everyone can answer quite a few of them and
监管机构、保险承运人，几乎每个人都能回答其中的不少问题，并通过将他们的软件部署到云端来从中获得收益。
generate revenue from it by put their software in the cloud.
通过将他们的软件部署到云端来从中获得收益。
But they at some point, there needs to be safe, secure ways to
但是在某个时候，需要有安全可靠的方法来
let others in my opinion, but, as I said, I try to avoid the politics.
但正如我所说，我尽量避免涉及政治。
I'm not trying to scare away auto manufacturers and
我并不是想吓跑汽车制造商和
that's going to eventually come from the regulators, I believe.
这最终将由监管机构来决定，我相信。
>> Yeah, it as someone who's technical myself,
是的，作为一个技术人员，
I'm gonna stay agnostic as to what the right policies are and
我会保持中立，不去判断哪些政策是正确的，
even if you talk to different OEMs they have.
即使你与不同的原始设备制造商(OEMs)交谈，他们也会有。
I'll admit they have radically different points of view as
我承认他们有着截然不同的观点，因为
to how much they want to sort of control when and have.
他们想要在何时拥有某种程度的控制权。
Sort of essentially ownership of that data.
某种程度上是对那些数据的所有权。
I mean I can speak for before that our view is generally, it's for
我是说，就我们以前的观点而言，通常我们认为，这是为了~!@#$%^&*()
fleet donors it belongs that the the data is kind of theirs to control and.
他们认为数据是他们可以控制的财产。
We're fairly actively looking at ways that the data can be shared within
我们正在积极探索数据可以在...内共享的方式。
the context of the privacy principles that we as an industry have adopted.
我们作为一个行业所采纳的隐私原则的背景。
Which really it's about respecting customer's ability to
这确实是关于尊重客户的能力去
kind of decide that data needs to be used for.
这确实是关于尊重客户的能力去决定那些数据需要被使用。But back to Ted's previous point.
But back to Ted's previous point.
但回到泰德之前的观点。
A lot of it's a it's a heavy optimization in terms of how
很多方面都进行了大量的优化，特别是在如何……上。
much data is collected by what and for what purpose and
大量的数据由什么收集以及用于什么目的，以及……
there's a lot of effort, especially.
有很多努力，特别是……
When you get beyond prototype vehicles into sort of the,
当你超越了原型车辆进入到某种……
the mass large fleet to collect only the minimal that's that's needed to.
为了收集仅仅所需的最少量，大规模的车队。
To sort of get the job done.
为了完成工作。
And even retaining that I think one of our data scientists at one point
为了完成工作，我们的一位数据科学家曾经主张要实时收集每辆车的完整画布。
had argued I want to collect the entire canvas in real time for every vehicle.
他曾主张我想要实时收集每辆车的完整画布。
And they then came and said we need, we need,
他们随后来说，我们需要，我们需要，
four petabytes per year of have to be able to sort of store all of that and
每年需要四个拍字节的存储空间来存储所有这些数据。
that's just the canvas to point that that's.
这只是用来指出那个的画布。
Typically sliced up in either one second or multi slices per second intervals and
通常按照每秒一切片或每秒多切片的间隔来切分，
a lot of that data isn't really that interesting for day to day use.
很多那样的数据对于日常使用来说并不是那么有趣。
But to researchers, It can be of much more interest and
但对于研究人员来说，它可能会更有趣，
then when you compute the data costs to try
然后，当你计算尝试处理数据的成本时，
to do anything with that data collecting it at that kind of scale.
处理这种规模数据收集的任何事情。
It's just astronomical and not practical.
它简直是天文数字，不切实际。
>> Great.
>> 太好了。
Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，迈克。
There's a side conversation going on in the chatroom about
聊天室里正在进行一场旁边的对话。
the NBN security model, which I know our panelists are not entirely familiar with.
在NBN安全模型中，我知道我们的小组成员并不完全熟悉。
But in the NBN security model, the data itself is secured so
但在NBN安全模型中，数据本身是得到了保护的，所以
the name is attached to the data and then there's a cryptographic signature.
数据附有名称，然后有一个加密签名。
That is attached to it.
这是附加在它上面的。
And of the people on the chat room are wondering whether we could,
以及聊天室里的人们都在想我们是否可以，
given that security model.
鉴于那种安全模型。
We can bypass the cloud and then not rely on security
我们可以绕过云端，然后不依赖于安全 mechanisms provided, by the cloud and then simply have the data.
mechanisms provided, by the cloud and then simply have the data.
我们可以简单地拥有数据，而不依赖于云提供的安全机制。
I'll go to researchers directly.
我将直接去找研究人员。
But I'll let the conversation go on for a little more.
但我会让对话再继续一会儿。
So I'm thinking this was this was really nice and.
所以我在想，这真的很好。
The other NDN related point here is to
The other NDN related point here is to ~!@#$%^&*()
Ted's point about standardizing the data.
泰德关于标准化数据的观点。
It comes to standardizing the data names and this is very much an NDN.
它涉及到标准化数据名称，这在很大程度上是NDN的内容。
Topic where in NDN, the focus of networking is around naming the data and
在NDN中，网络的焦点集中在对数据进行命名上，而不是命名你可以检索数据的端点。
not naming the endpoint where you can retrieve it.
不是命名你可以检索数据的端点。
And it seems to me that there's a nice collaboration opportunity here
看来在这里有一个很好的合作机会。
to look at how the Indian naming works.
探究印度命名是如何运作的。
And create name spaces that could be derived
并创建可以派生的命名空间
from standardizing the data, that could be obtained from vehicles.
从标准化可以从车辆中获取的数据。
Okay.
好的。
So we're coming closer to the end, and
所以我们接近尾声了，
I wanted to first give an opportunity to the panelists,
所以首先我想给小组成员一个机会，
to see if there's any questions that you guys wanted to ask each other.
所以首先我想给小组成员一个机会，看看你们是否有想要互相提问的问题。Before I throw in one final question.
Before I throw in one final question.
在我提出最后一个问题之前。
Given what you've heard from everybody, go ahead Teddy.
在你从每个人那里听到的基础上，继续吧，泰迪。
>> Well sort of ties into the NDN thing you're talking about.
这在某种程度上与你所提到的NDN事情有关。
So, and sort of an earlier question as far as
那么，就像之前的问题一样，到某种程度上
automotive Ethernet, and sort of.
汽车以太网，以及诸如此类的技术。
And you're also asking how the, this community can potentially help automotive
您还在询问，这个社区如何可能帮助汽车行业。
manufacturers there is cost associated with all this that they're trying
制造商们正在尝试的所有这些事情都与成本相关联。
to balance against, sort of capabilities, security, all these things.
要权衡的是，某种程度上的能力、安全性，所有这些因素。
I want to see these patches take place in the vehicle.
我希望看到这些修补工作能在车辆上进行。
I realize this may take some time and some evolution because I've like to see
我意识到这可能需要一些时间和一些演变，因为我想看到
currently the most vehicles operate on can and other other bus networks.
目前，大多数车辆运行在CAN和其他车用总线网络上。
That is very limited bandwidth.
这是非常有限的带宽。
Its broadcast is a trusted network.
它的广播是一个可信赖的网络。
Anything can impersonate anything else,
任何事物都可以冒充其他事物，
which is not a good thing if you can break into that network.
如果你能侵入那个网络，这并不是一件好事。
So I like to us to see move closer to
所以我希望我们能够更近一步地看到~!@#$%^&*()
Ethernet sign messages not encrypted and
以太网信号消息未加密，且
then so that you know you can't have people sort of other devices that can.
然后，这样你就知道了，你不能让其他设备之类的进来。
Be compromised find their way or apps or whatever find their way in there and
被破坏，让它们或是应用程序或其他什么东西找到方法进入那里，并且
be able to sort of eavesdrop in and send.
能够有点像偷听一样进入并发送。
Bogus instructions cuz that's futurist so I think that anyway,
虚假的指示，因为那是未来主义的，所以我认为无论如何，
I'd like to sort of encourage further dialogue with
我想在一定程度上鼓励进一步的对话与~!@#$%^&*()
NSD community and an auto manufacturers and
NSD社区和汽车制造商
to sort of Lend them your expertise.
向他们提供你的专业知识。
Looking at town now, hopefully sort of jumped in on that.
现在看着镇上，希望有点介入其中了。
>> Did you want to jump in?
>> 你想要介入吗？
>> I thought that was a very good thought.
>> 我认为那是一个非常好的想法。
And so I don't have anything further to add there.
所以我没有更多要补充的了。
I was just wondering I have sort of a related question I was just wondering.
所以我有一个相关的问题我想问一下。
I do agree that standardisation is important.
我同意标准化是重要的。
And for data and the sharing of the data will be helpful.
对于数据以及数据的共享将会是有帮助的。
I do recognize sort of the challenges that you're doing that and
我确实认识到你在做这件事时所面临的那些挑战。
the privacy and the cost and everything.
隐私、成本以及所有相关事宜。
And so I'm wondering whether it makes sense,
因此，我在思考这是否有意义，
for example, for a fund, a neutral entity.
例如，对于一个基金来说，一个中立的实体。
To host the data so you can sort of anonymize the data,
托管数据以便可以对数据进行匿名处理，
trying to get rid of the identifying information that
试图去除能够识别身份的信息，
will sort of implicate any car maker, particular car models or so on.
将会涉及任何汽车制造商，特定的汽车型号等。
And so that neutral entity can host the data and then provide
因此，那个中立实体可以托管数据，然后提供
the aggregation of the data to users.
数据聚合给用户。
So that data may not only be useful for researchers, but also be very useful for
因此，这些数据不仅对研究人员有用，而且对于
validating the vehicle performance, especially autonomous cars.
验证车辆性能，尤其是自动驾驶汽车。
As we all know, validating autonomous car performance and
确保自动驾驶汽车性能的验证工作，众所周知，
safety is still a big challenge.
安全仍然是一个巨大的挑战。
And [COUGH] so we don't have enough data [LAUGH] to do for
而且（咳咳），因此我们没有足够的数据来做……（笑声）
anybody sort of beyond the carmakers themselves to test their cars.
任何人，除了汽车制造商自己之外，都可以测试他们的汽车。
And there is like of standardization or even what do you mean?
还有，就是缺乏标准化，或者说你的意思是什么？
How do we even measure safety?
我们如何才能衡量安全性呢？
So, I think standardization and along those lines will be tremendously helpful.
所以，我认为标准化及其相关方面将极大地有所帮助。
>> Okay great.
>> 好的，很棒。
Any comments from the other panelists on this one?
其他小组成员对此有何评论？
Cuz I think we're coming up to the end.
因为我觉得我们快要结束了。
>> [COUGH] standards, I agree.
标准，我同意。
[LAUGH] I think data standardization is always important and talking with folks.
[笑声] 我认为数据标准化总是很重要，与人交谈时也是如此。
It took SAE and some of the other organizations probably
SAE和其他一些组织可能花了很多年时间才
numerous years to standardize on sort of data and
花费了很多年时间来对某种数据进行标准化，并且
all of the things around right to repair and all that.
花费了很多年时间来对某种数据进行标准化，并且，随着时间的推移，我怀疑其他很多与维修权相关的事物也会如此。
And over over time, I suspect a lot of the other sort of
随着时间的推移，我怀疑其他很多类似的事物也会如此。
data elements need to be standardized.
数据元素需要标准化。
It's just a question of what, when and where.
这只是一个关于什么、何时和在哪里的问题。
And then getting things into the standardized format.
然后将事物转换成标准化的格式。
>> Okay, great.
好的，太棒了。
Thank you, Mike.
谢谢你，迈克。
So I think at this point, we can wrap up the panel.
所以我认为此时我们可以结束这个小组讨论了。
So thank you, Mike.
所以，谢谢你，迈克。
Thank you, Ted.
谢谢你，泰德。
Thank you, Tao.
谢谢你，陶。
Wonderful conversation.
精彩的对话。
Really appreciate you taking the time and
非常感谢您抽出时间来
educating us a little bit about the automotive world.
教育我们一些关于汽车世界的知识。
It's a fascinating space, I think.
这是一个迷人的空间，我认为。
I hope that more networking researchers will look at the automotive world and
我希望更多的网络研究人员将目光投向汽车领域，
all the very interesting problems that are coming up.
因为汽车领域出现了许多非常有趣的问题。
So thank you again.
再次感谢您。
And at this point, I think I wanna pass this back to the [INAUDIBLE] folks and
在这一点上，我想我要把这个问题传回给[听不清楚]的人员，还有
see if IIya is back on line.
看看伊利亚是否已经重新在线上了。
And if you wanted to talk about fabric.
如果你想谈论布料。
>> Thank you everyone.
>> 谢谢大家。